<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on BlakeAnneberg.com</title>
    <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on BlakeAnneberg.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 20:13:46 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>More Practice More Game</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/more_practice_more_games/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 01 Jan 2026 20:13:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/more_practice_more_games/</guid>
      <description>I need to get back in the habit of Godot study.
There are a couple reasons I dropped off&amp;hellip;
Focusing more on Boot.dev which is Python study right now. I want to keep my streak alive for January, and I am using Boots alot to help&amp;hellip; but I feel like I am learning too. I want to run more. I want to make time to exercise as a highest priority of the entire day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>NM UT WY</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/nm_ut_wy/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 30 Dec 2025 08:59:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/nm_ut_wy/</guid>
      <description>I cant wait to inlcude these passenger rail routes. But first I need to go back and visit them in person.
During our dev meeting today, we talked about going the extra mile, and the dev re-phrased it as &amp;ldquo;Travel extra trip, its always worth it.&amp;rdquo;
I think doing a road trip to these locations would be worth the extra trip.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remote Worker</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/remote_worker/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Dec 2025 18:22:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/remote_worker/</guid>
      <description>I was thinking of being a remote worker&amp;hellip; for my self.
The Steam Fest deadline is fast approaching and I think only the store page has to be published for me to put my application in for Jan 5th.
I have so many ideas using the game engine that I am looking forward to implementing them&amp;hellip; but I am also thinking of making more time for doing the development work. So I am looking forward to being a remote self-worker some day.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold Scate Ski</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cold_scate_ski/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Dec 2025 11:35:37 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cold_scate_ski/</guid>
      <description>The snow has been so bad that finally there was 3 inches that fell and I went out to the Nordic Center.
First, it was really cold, with wind, so maybe it was in the single digits, but around 13 on my car.
Second, the snow blew away from the exposed areas of the trail, which were hard to see.
Third, I just had waxed them and now there are some areas where rocks and pebbles which tore up my new wax and make alot of rips into the actual skis.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Animal Game</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/animal_game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 27 Dec 2025 11:54:01 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/animal_game/</guid>
      <description>Well, without the main game finished yet, I want to use the game engine as a animal game, where the animal is going on a journey. I think its pretty analogous the current game loop.
Some goals for the animal game:
Educational: You can learn about the animal, the location and environment it lives in, as well as other things about humans impact. Partner with other groups to develop it: Need subject matter experts Raise money for preservation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Start Projects</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/start_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 25 Dec 2025 14:34:34 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/start_projects/</guid>
      <description>I am really looking forward to starting new projects/hobbies.
Using Godot and Python knowledge to start work on a game that uses the Game engine for CRG to then create a new game that centes around either hiking or biking and another game that focues on sustainable construction. I am also learing pixel art and want to develop this game with Youtube Vlogs. Learn bagpipes, hopefully with a digital chanter. Ardueno&amp;hellip; Now just need to carve out time to work on it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>YT Vlog</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/yt_vlog/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Dec 2025 17:43:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/yt_vlog/</guid>
      <description>UPDATE: Just created it!
I am really thinking of starting a YT account for the video game.
Not really sure how it will be but having a dedicated channel, but it might be a good idea.
Espically if the game will have expansions like new content and routes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>DevOps Room Layout</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/room_layout/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Dec 2025 23:05:22 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/room_layout/</guid>
      <description>I am interested about Kubernetes as I keep watching Youtube videos about linux and also want to learn about Docker and containers, so this week at work I learned about Ansible for Cisco networking equipment. I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know the difference between all these technologies, so I stumbled across this metaphor after Googling for the differences between them:
For a room: &amp;ldquo;Terraform builds the room, Ansible furnishes the room and Kubernetes manages the room&amp;rsquo;s operation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Upload Time</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/upload_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 16 Dec 2025 08:31:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/upload_time/</guid>
      <description>Its finally time to upload the first ever build of the game.
Very greatfull for the help and work that has been put into the game.
The game is still pretty rough but at least its a version that is playable.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Finnish Music</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/finnish_music/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Dec 2025 19:10:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/finnish_music/</guid>
      <description>I am really liking listing to music from Finland. Its pretty much all YLE Radio Suomi.
I wish I was there listening to it in the car or on a train.
I really hope I can create a rail game in finland and spend more time there experiencing Finland culture.
Then at the same time I can make the sauna game, run marathons, and swim in lakes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FTP and Game Development</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/ftp_and_game_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Dec 2025 18:17:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/ftp_and_game_development/</guid>
      <description>I learned about about FTP and how important a measure it is when assessing workouts and life fitness. During the FTP test, you have to hit maximum effort to measure the about of Co2 and o2, which is not very fun to do. But the end result is a number that is unique and you will be able to plan workouts better.
Otherwise, how does FTP and video game development have in common?</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Skinning &amp; Gaming</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/skinning_gaming/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 04 Dec 2025 19:02:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/skinning_gaming/</guid>
      <description>Skinning is really fun, if a bit sweaty. One idea is to do video game vlog updates while skinning up the mountain.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blender and Plants</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/blender_and_plants/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 23:00:01 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/blender_and_plants/</guid>
      <description>Blender, the 3d modeling software and plants have something in common.
Well seeds of plants.
I want to be able to make things in Blender and use them as assets in games. I also have seeds for plants, and I want to be inspired to make little 3d terrariums.
I also want to do a couple things daily.
Make time for exercise every day. Do couple lessons of Boot.Dev, Godot on GameDev.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Shortwave</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/shortwave/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Dec 2025 14:55:39 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/shortwave/</guid>
      <description>I am so glad to learn about shortwave.
My top channels are:
Shonan Beach FM YLE RAdio Suomi Helsiniki BBC Scotland BBC Radio 1 SR.SE and some Danish channels I like Jazz and hearing new music I would not normally hear.
Wish my Andorid phone had shortwave.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stoic Routines</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/stoic_routines/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Dec 2025 22:30:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/stoic_routines/</guid>
      <description>This is a foundation of of stoic thought. Some of mine are:
Exercise every day Learn a bit of code (boot.dev python, Go, CCNA) Work on the video game or learn Godot or pixel art or Blender Try and wake up early Writing out helps put distance to see a new perspective. Basically its structure and systems to make me productive.
But also I don&amp;rsquo;t get upset as I have to be flexible if I don&amp;rsquo;t have enough time for the routine.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vim motions in Godot</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/vim_motions_in_godot/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Nov 2025 13:11:47 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/vim_motions_in_godot/</guid>
      <description>I am so glad to use Vim motions in Godot script editor.
I was having such a painful time using mouse. Now I can work so much easier places just with keyboard. I also like Godot having a LSP, so I dont have to remember everything about the syntax.
I hope that Godot can be my first real life coding win. I never really did any Javascript or Go project, so Godot script will hopefully be my first.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Nordic Center</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/nordic_center/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Nov 2025 18:48:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/nordic_center/</guid>
      <description>Going to the Nordic center is always nice.
I know one person over there and its nice to talk to him and hear about all things Nordic skiing. Also I like the clothing which is also what I wear for skinning.
Last night it snowed a bit, so it was almost enough to try classic skiing.
When the trail officially opens, the restaurant opens and sells unlimited soup, which is nice after being cold.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn Godot</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learn_godot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Nov 2025 09:16:55 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learn_godot/</guid>
      <description>Its been a number of months since I first purchased my Godot learning course. Finally this week I have sat down and started to learn it. With all tutorials, its pretty slow going at first. But its forcing me to think creatively and learning something new is always fun.
I purchased the course on GameDev.TV and then they had more sales so I purchased a drawing course, and a Blender course, pixel art course which Ill learn Asprite.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More Game Ideas</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/more_game_ideas/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Nov 2025 09:15:29 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/more_game_ideas/</guid>
      <description>Well, I have more game ideas.
Putting in CO Rail Game the idea about riding bikes, and even kayaking are enough to re-scope out the game, and I would love Sauna to go in there too.
What these two things would do is to closely align with European ideas of sustainable transportation, preserving nature, traveling across borders, and social responsibility and equality with Finnish Sauna ideas.
&amp;ldquo;The Finish sauna is a great equalizer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold Running Season</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cold_running_season/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 24 Nov 2025 17:42:53 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cold_running_season/</guid>
      <description>Its dark out when I go run at 5pm. Its also cold.
I now have to wear pants, gloves, hat, and potentially multiple layers for jacket.
I have to watch out for ice, uneven surfaces and potentially bring lights.
Not linking it.
But I am looking forward to skate skiing in the dark.
What would be better is to go run in the morning. But ill have to dress up even more and wake up super early in the morning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>One Game Loop; Multiple Games</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/one_game_loop_multiple_games/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 23 Nov 2025 18:20:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/one_game_loop_multiple_games/</guid>
      <description>Before I write about the blog title, I wanted to replace in Neovim the underlines of _ with spaces of my Hugo markdown file title name which is title: &amp;quot;One Game Loop Multiple Games&amp;quot; so after a bit of googling I figure out that its :%s/_/ /gc.
Right now I am listing to VLE Radio Suomi Helsinki and its all in Finnish and sounds kinda country music.
I wish I knew Finish and Swedish, Danish and Norwegian.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Green Tea and smoothies</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/green_tea/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 22 Nov 2025 10:33:26 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/green_tea/</guid>
      <description>I really like hot or cold green, jasmine pearl, black, or chai tea.
I also like smoothies which have frozen blueberries, bananas, strawberries.
Typically I like smoothies after I work out. Tea is nice in the morning up to mid day.
Loose leaf tea is also nice, and I would like to do this more often as I feel that tea bags have less quality tea or have plastic.
Its hard to believe how much work it is to make tea, and how to hard it is to learn how tea ceremonies are performed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Freemium with DLC</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/freemium_with_dlc/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 18 Nov 2025 08:41:41 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/freemium_with_dlc/</guid>
      <description>In releasing the video game, its interesting to think about how to pay for development costs.
If the game were released as free, with core game mechanics, then it will be downloaded alot.
Then we release paid DLC with expanded game play, its hard to know how much that DLC should cost.
I don&amp;rsquo;t often buy totally free games, and then purchase DLC.
The model is usually paying for the game up front first, and then getting additional DLC.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Space and Exploration</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/space_and_exploration/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Nov 2025 18:59:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/space_and_exploration/</guid>
      <description>I have always enjoyed space and watching videos about live stream of rocket launches and videos about space exploration.
I also love video games about space like Starfield and Civ Alpha Centauri and Surviving Mars.
I just wish we could have more robotic exploration of all the planets of the solar system.
Like have a live webcam satellites at each planet.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning Sunlight</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/morning_sunlight/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Nov 2025 14:54:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/morning_sunlight/</guid>
      <description>Cannot overstate how much I like sunlight.
While reading a brief section about Onsens in Letter from Japan by Marie Kondo, she descrubes a dawn ceder bath experience. It was such a nice image in my mind by the way she described the light coming though and the wood, steam and water sounds.
Truely a wonderful experience in life is that orange light of the morning coming in though the windows and being able to wake up, warm up, and feel refreshed so early in the morning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Travel Without Leaving</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/travel_without_leaving/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Nov 2025 08:44:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/travel_without_leaving/</guid>
      <description>I really like to travel, and I also like to play video games that make it so I can travel without leaving my current location.
Civilization, Starfield and even City Skylines are games that make me think I cam traveling around.
I also like cooking up dishes that I ate when I traveled.
This includes food from India, Japan and Scotland.
I am so glad to be making a video game that makes it so you can travel virtually and also be able learn about food from other cultures.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Plans</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/video_game_plans/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Nov 2025 16:53:37 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/video_game_plans/</guid>
      <description>I am really looking forward for this plan that revolves around being a indi dev.
Learn more Python, Godot and how to realase game on Steam, during all these stages. Release CO Rail Game. Release add ons that expand on the content with locations around the world. Release Sauna Game that is similar to CO Rail Game with static images and text and buttons. Release Coorie Home that could be 3D modeled with Blender and use Godot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stories Art People</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/stories_art_people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 24 Oct 2025 09:04:38 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/stories_art_people/</guid>
      <description>In making the vie game, I am so excited about the kinds of stories I can share, the artwork of the locations and the characters that a player will come across.
It is so different to make up things and share them.
Creating a video game requires so much creativity and technical know how. It can really tie together so many mediums. You don&amp;rsquo;t need a lot of space, expensive gear or materials.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Great Scott Railway</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/great_scott_railway/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Oct 2025 20:09:28 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/great_scott_railway/</guid>
      <description>In building the video game, and it getting released, it really feels like a railroad getting built.
Large up front cost, and hopefully making money on it.
In building future routes, I hope I can travel and do research.
Eventually heading up to Scotland and doing a route up there.
ScotRail names these routes, as Great Scenic Lines, but I kinda like Great Scot Lines.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Seeds and Starting</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/seeds_and_starting/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Sep 2025 08:42:44 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/seeds_and_starting/</guid>
      <description>I have a lot of different seed packets, and I need to start using them.
I thought I would do this over the summer and have plants on the deck. But I got really busy and did not start them.
So its looking more and more likely that I will do them indoors over Fall and Winter.
Not sure if this is a good idea. But I have all the equipment and soil.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cowboy Bebop and Commonplace Writing</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cowboy_bebop_and_commonplace_writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Sep 2025 22:32:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cowboy_bebop_and_commonplace_writing/</guid>
      <description>Listening to Shonan Beach FM, late night Jazz, which made me think of the Jazz in Cowboy Bebop as I have been thinking about Cowboys lately with the research for the Colorado Rail Game.
While I haven&amp;rsquo;t learned about ranching, cattle or individual Cowboys or the likes of Buffalo Bill, I am surrounded by books, stories and myths that drew people west. The public library has my old railroad books next to the history of Colorado as I go though all the books looking for railroad information.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ancient Rome</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/ancient_rome/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Aug 2025 17:49:14 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/ancient_rome/</guid>
      <description>Where does one start.
Rome is so old, that you literally have to go down layers of dirt and dust in order to find it.
There are many things that makes me interested in Rome, but what really surprises me is that I just was there. I never thought I would visit again. Some things that make me interested in Rome.
I really like ancient Roman houses with a center courtyard with water.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Straw Bale Game Coorie Home</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/straw_bale_game_coorie_home/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Aug 2025 07:35:44 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/straw_bale_game_coorie_home/</guid>
      <description>I have been thinking about about this future project.
Yesterday I watched a video by indi Game Clinic who was talking about Game Loops. And he basically said for solo/indi game devs not to worry about game loops and rather focus on the treasure chests. These treasure chests are the individual components that make your game fun&amp;hellip; and once you have enough of them, you can combine them into a game loop.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blue Sky and Green Fields</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/blue_sky_and_green_fields/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Aug 2025 21:07:01 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/blue_sky_and_green_fields/</guid>
      <description>Post Ironman I am struck by how much free time I have.
I feel that its a good time to think about the blue sky and green fields.
Basically what do I want to fill my time with next&amp;hellip; aka blue sky.
And how do I want to start fresh&amp;hellip; green fields.
For blue sky:
Video game creation. Cook more. Grow plants indoors more. More weights and yoga. For green fields its pretty much all the same items above as I will be starting from pretty much a blank slate, but with some guidance:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPH Sports</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cph_sports/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Aug 2025 13:34:29 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cph_sports/</guid>
      <description>Reasons to enjoy CPH Marathon and Triathalon.
Really fun city to run though. Nice to be at sea level. Nice weather. Runner community. Nice landscape and routes. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunflowers</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sunflowers/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Aug 2025 10:14:04 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sunflowers/</guid>
      <description>Out of all the seeds that are planted I feel like sunflowers are some of the easist to grow.
I really like the many different kinds of sunflowers.
Sunflowers mean many differnet things:
Bright hopefull flowers that follow the sun Utility of the seeds and polination for bees Fast growth and strong stocks. Large leaves soaking up energy. Multiple flowers on each stock. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Orange and Game</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/orange_and_game/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Aug 2025 17:37:42 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/orange_and_game/</guid>
      <description>Its been a while since the last post. Been busy with Ironman training and video game Travel by Train.
But after going to an opening of a brand new building as a artist in resident house, it really was cool to think of some of the connections to this new house.
Its one big room. Has a very large door window. Mettle cladding roof and shell. All white inside.
It looks very prefabricated, and I wish it straw bale house</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Summer Jazz</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/summer_jazz/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Jul 2025 10:54:45 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/summer_jazz/</guid>
      <description>Listening to Shonan Beach FM and wishing I could take a flight to Tokyo and spend the summer on the beach learning how to surf.
Other things I could do there:
Work on the video game Learn japanese cooking Learn gardening Go bike riding Work in a coffee shop Learn how to sail Learn Japanese Anyway, I am ready to endure the hot summer with Jazz.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Training and Learning</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/training_and_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Jun 2025 09:24:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/training_and_learning/</guid>
      <description>Pretty much doing full time Ironman training and then squeezing any other time into Godot/Video Game learning.
Three things I want to focus on is weight workouts&amp;hellip; and Game Design Document mixed in with more tutorials on Godot from humble bumble.
I also want to get a desk on wheels that can also be a standing desk.
I have kinda given up on Network+ study as I just don&amp;rsquo;t have time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ideas during exercise</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/ideas_during_exercise/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Jun 2025 19:56:54 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/ideas_during_exercise/</guid>
      <description>The two game ideas I had are:
Give train cars different names and themes. Really customize the view out of the train car to the location its passing. I like connecting local environment of animals like the rabbit I saw and the anvil cloud that was in the distance to something that might make the game feel more localized to the land its in.
Cant wait to actually learn how to code and git it in the game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rail vs Train</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/rail_vs_train/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 13 Jun 2025 21:07:04 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/rail_vs_train/</guid>
      <description>Finally figured out the name, Travel By Train, but having second thoughts from the original Colorado Rail Game name.
I am really releaved to have figured out the name.
Now I just want concentrate on making the game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Godot thoughts</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/godot_thoughts/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Jun 2025 15:55:40 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/godot_thoughts/</guid>
      <description>I really like Godots idea and ethers.
I have been learning from YouTube videos alot about game design and I am pretty confident that I can make UI&amp;hellip; but then I am not 100% what to do for so many different scenes.
I also been learning about game design. I am so glad there are so many free and open source materials.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>No Headphones</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/no_headphones/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 31 May 2025 22:13:26 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/no_headphones/</guid>
      <description>I forgot to get my headphones for the long bike ride. But I really enjoyed just hearing the bird song in the parks, the other noises of biking and just being present.
I know during races, headphones are discouraged. But I think Ill try and use headphones less for training.
With &amp;lsquo;No Headphones&amp;rsquo; I also think I could do away with less phone use, less YouTube, less Reddit, and more game dev study, more reading books, more time doing things I want to do like going outside.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SBR</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sbr/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 30 May 2025 21:59:36 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sbr/</guid>
      <description>Swim. Bike. Run.
Yesterday I did a bike and then run. This morning I swam, and should have don&amp;rsquo;t weights. Tomorrow I will do long bike and fast run.
I like it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind Map Game Dev</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/mind_map_game_dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 May 2025 09:07:52 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/mind_map_game_dev/</guid>
      <description>I have been using Jira for all my todo&amp;rsquo;s but I was reminded from a YouTube, https://www.youtube.com/watch?v=Q1TzYZ6kf8U, and that you can use a Mind Map for task management.
I really like it as I can see my tasks easier and I can see all the tasks in one view.
There were so many Jira tasks, I was having hard time seeing everything. Having things in mind map I can now move things around and op and close things better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPH TLL HEL</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cph_tll_hel/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 May 2025 01:13:23 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cph_tll_hel/</guid>
      <description>More than half way though the journey and races. Things I learned in CPH:
Biking is fun and easy Going with gut feeling and pushing hard in the marathon was successful Learn more about recycling Train journeys are fun Spa day is fun Things I learned I learned in TLL:
Traveling with friend is better than being by myself Bog running is fun Waterfall is nice but with a mint chocolate hot chocolate with waterfall is nicer Tallinn is easy and nice to visit Cant wait to learn more in HEL.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rail game planning</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/rail_game_planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 06 May 2025 08:43:08 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/rail_game_planning/</guid>
      <description>Done with phase one meaning we go onto phase two.
Turns out its not that simple.
Phase two is actually MVP0, MVP1 and MVP2.
MVP0 is wrap up tasks from Phase one and set stage better for the next stages:
Finalize wire frames. Get initial play testing completed. Plan out narritive for crowdfunding, then launch crowdfunding, launch merch store. MVP1 is using funds to get a very very core game loop running with code.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Old laptop i3 and rofi</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/old_laptop_i3_and_rofi/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 May 2025 12:09:54 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/old_laptop_i3_and_rofi/</guid>
      <description>I have had this old laptop for three years and I like using fedora on it with i3.
However in i3, I am really not liking dmenu.
I cant find chrome as its like downloaded though gnome or something. So the other day I learned about Rofi from a Arch ricing YouTube video.
I saw that it did exactly what gnome did in like PopOS!.
So I installed it but now I need to figure out how to make it the main application manager and retire dmenu forever.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Three story lines</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/three_story_lines/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 02 May 2025 08:05:15 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/three_story_lines/</guid>
      <description>After the video game meeting I still want to develop three eras of the game, Modern Colorado, Gold Rush Colorado and Modern Ukraine.
But its probably bad developing three story lines at the same time as this is a huge scope. With over a hundred assets (historical stories, people stories, places to visit, things to buy) for just one story line, so that might be over 300 to 400 assets.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starting Plants From Seeds</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/starting_plants_from_seeds/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Apr 2025 08:20:43 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/starting_plants_from_seeds/</guid>
      <description>I really am looking forward to starting plants from seeds. I have the trays, seeds, warming mat. Just need to figure out what I am going to plant.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sun Shower</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sun_shower/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 28 Apr 2025 17:51:52 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sun_shower/</guid>
      <description>Had all the seasons yesterday and today. From 81 to 28 in 24 hours.
Saw no clouds yesterday to today driving in a near whiteout.
I was biking and working how fast I was going to get sun burnt. Then I was swimming and wondering if I was going to be chilled.
I liked being warm and having the wind keep me cool. I like seeing the sun shower illuminate the new green leaves of the trees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Going back to Python</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/going_back_to_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 18 Apr 2025 17:39:17 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/going_back_to_python/</guid>
      <description>Cant help but go back to Python as I saw a &amp;ldquo;Coding for Beginners&amp;rdquo; book in the public library.
It seems to be pretty easy to understand.
However in my Nvim setup I didnt have a Python LSP.
So after working on that its finally up and running&amp;hellip; but I dont have auto complete figured out.
Will try figuring out the config file to get that up and running. Glad to be 1/3rd into the book.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First Rain</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/first_rain/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 16 Apr 2025 18:33:17 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/first_rain/</guid>
      <description>First impressions of the first rain.
So am so glad it rained, as it means winters over. It smelled so wet and good. Its going to help the plants bloom faster. It cleaned my car. It means summer is here. Saw a rainbow over snow. Sounded like rain. Ready for more rain!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Game</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sustainable_game/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 18:21:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sustainable_game/</guid>
      <description>Sustanable in the sence that I can pay to create and maintain them. The video game business plans I am working on.
Create game, crowdfund. Have content expansions, paid or donate? Merch store, paid. The second meaning of &amp;ldquo;Sustainability&amp;rdquo; is that the game is focused on building a straw bale house and using renewable resources and construction materials sustainability.
It would be like learning about sustainable construction techniques and then plopping down assets on a 2Dmap to build a house.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Yoga</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/yoga/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Apr 2025 15:35:46 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/yoga/</guid>
      <description>Yoga was not taught in my school&amp;hellip; or high school or collage. Stretching was taught super early. I would say Yoga is similar to swimming. Stretching is similar to perhaps weight lifting, where its super specific, and you have to learn the correct way.
Yoga and swimming are so similar with breathing and pretty much the flow. If you don&amp;rsquo;t do it regularly, it can be a wakeup for your body.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fika homage</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/fika_homage/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Apr 2025 21:12:37 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/fika_homage/</guid>
      <description>After a long run yesterday, and with today being cooler, than I thought so I push it physically again. I am so glad to have pushed it and gone all the way to Fika coffee.
It was really nice to ride. Biking out to a scandi coffee place is even nicer. Thats why I go out there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Tired to bike</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/tired_to_bike/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Apr 2025 19:48:58 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/tired_to_bike/</guid>
      <description>I came back early to get on the trainer and bike. It was so warm out that I wanted to ride in the streets, but there are still a ton on black rocks from winter on the road and shoulder.
So here I am writing about being too tired to bike when I should just get on the bike and do it.
Now I am listening to Jazz. I really need to get a bike just for commuting and go around on that.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hot Tub vs Steam Room vs Sauna</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/hot_tub_vs_steam_room_vs_sauna/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Apr 2025 18:24:05 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/hot_tub_vs_steam_room_vs_sauna/</guid>
      <description>Post-tourist rush, I finally got to enjoy the gym&amp;rsquo;s amenities! Sadly, the sauna remains out of order, but I did test out the hot tub and steam room. Here&amp;rsquo;s my quick ranking:
Sauna (with cold plunge): Best overall for feeling refreshed, especially with Saunagus. Hot Tub: Excellent for pure relaxation and warming up. Steam Room (with eucalyptus): Good, but needs eucalyptus spray to be truly enjoyable. Fingers crossed the sauna gets fixed soon!</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Phases of Game Development</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/phases_of_game_development/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Apr 2025 08:27:23 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/phases_of_game_development/</guid>
      <description>I didn&amp;rsquo;t really know phases till I was in them. Trying to think of these phases and be able to have a successful game.
Phase 0.
Have idea. Reach out to group to see if they can help. They reply back that they can help and scope out idea. Group proposes phases. Phase 1.
Group breaks up dev into two Phases. Phase 1 will have UXUI and game engine/flow scoped out, as well as content of game figured out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Treadmill reading</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/treadmill_reading/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Apr 2025 08:55:59 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/treadmill_reading/</guid>
      <description>I read on the treadmill. Couple factors play into this.
The treadmill faces a wall and has no TV.
I have the Libby app and public libary access.
My phone can display the text big enough to read while jogging slowly.
Its nice as I usually start falling asleep and getting a run and read in is good use of time.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Mind_Blown_Emoji</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/mind_blown_emoji/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 01 Apr 2025 17:44:58 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/mind_blown_emoji/</guid>
      <description>I had two mind blown emoji points today&amp;hellip;
First was in Neovim when you can put a curser on a word and press shift and 3 or # which highlight all instances of the work with a key stroke.
Second was learning about DDNS when the device doesnt have a IP address and is behind a network.
I cant wait to learn more about DDNS and get better with Neovim.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Uphill</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/uphill/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 30 Mar 2025 22:21:44 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/uphill/</guid>
      <description>I honestly didn&amp;rsquo;t think the path was plowed all the way.
I had first thought I would do a out and back. What I did not expect once I started was loops, water hazards, and just continuing uphill.
There were a couple other uphill moments. The fact that I was recovering from being sick, missing workouts and combining two into one, and then not knowing how to dress as it was cold and windy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>History</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/history/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 29 Mar 2025 19:33:54 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/history/</guid>
      <description>I learned about Amor Fati, which loosely means to accept and embrace fate in all aspects of life.
I think this is different from manifestation, but it has more to do with feelings. How you control how you feel and no matter what happens to you. You take control over perceptions and you basically say that&amp;rsquo;s great and move on.
So how does amor fati have to do with history? I am not sure, but in seeing the old prospector pits with mining tailings, rail roads that went bankrupt and towns that went bust, I wonder what percentage of them thought they were wishing for a different fate, or just accepted fate.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Commute by foot</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/commute_by_foot/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 27 Mar 2025 19:37:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/commute_by_foot/</guid>
      <description>I saw a news show about a Tempe development that is only by foot. They had dirt paths between the buildings to keep air cool and allow for rain to drain.
The interviewees said it felt like a small village in Italy or France.
I really like this community concept.
Also they had basically no parking for the people that lived there, just parking for some stores that are on the ground level.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>1000 lines of notes</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/1000_lines_of_notes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Mar 2025 19:11:43 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/1000_lines_of_notes/</guid>
      <description>I finally hit 1000 lines of notes in my CCNA Markdown file.
I haven&amp;rsquo;t been good with taking notes lately as I have been focusing on triathlon training and the rail game.
I also am getting closer to the point of getting into subnetting, which I cant wait to re-learn as its everywhere and is so important.
I also cant wait to do more Pearsons Network Simulator.
I just wanted to celebrate this milestone as its taken me a while to keep at it and take notes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game loop</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/game_loop/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Mar 2025 08:59:44 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/game_loop/</guid>
      <description>I am so glad I hired the team to help make the game.
I was starting to feel a bit nervious that we needed to re-visualize the game loop, and today they made the game loop with other information too.
We figured out the four main personas/people that you will play as.
We figured out the four main game lopps: historical, food, nature and social.
So now I am going to research over the weekend how to make dialog between the players charactor and NPC&amp;rsquo;s.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>FlyTo</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/flyto/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Mar 2025 21:55:00 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/flyto/</guid>
      <description>After buying flights for CPH and HEL for marathons, I want to book flights to other places too, including places I have been to:
Tokyo and Fukushima to eat food and see rural places Iceland to see lava and spas Scotland to run, spa, eat and drink and relax AU/NZ to have fun. And other places I have not been:
Hamburg or Rotterdam for Marathon Greece for food and history&amp;hellip; and marathon Hawaii or for palm trees So ya, it would be fun to fly more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Game Joy</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/game_joy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Mar 2025 09:00:42 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/game_joy/</guid>
      <description>I think I have more fun building the game vs playing the game.
It&amp;rsquo;s so new, but buiilding a game and seeing ideas come to life is super.
Its wayyy more expensive, but I feel I can eventually recoup the expense.
Its nice to also build something that mixes history, utopia and relaxing chill.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Cold Run</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/early_cold_run/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Mar 2025 09:04:43 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/early_cold_run/</guid>
      <description>I missed my workout yesterday, so unfortunately the workouts build up.
I was supposed to run 5 miles yesterday and then run 7 miles fast today.
So I just did the 5 miles, and it was around 27F. It was cold the whole way around while wearing shorts, singlet and jacket with hoodie.
I am really happy I did the run even though I was slow and I had to do loops to avoid construction.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable Dream home</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sustainable_dream_home/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Mar 2025 16:47:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sustainable_dream_home/</guid>
      <description>Some sustainable things I want in a dream home and property.
Inside:
Straw bale walls for sound isolation Colorado colors which are natural. Earthen floors. Earthen walls. Exercise room. Inner courtyard. Water fountain for sound/cooling in the courtyard. Kitchen with glass walls that can open in to courtyard. Study room that is quiet. Workout room with treadmill, trainer. Outside:
Deciduous trees or fruit trees. Garden for flowers/veggies. Organic pool long enough to do laps in it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sitting Outside</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sitting_outside/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 28 Feb 2025 21:43:25 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sitting_outside/</guid>
      <description>It was finally warm enough in the afternoon to sit outside.
I really miss warmer climates.
Eventually went back in, as it was a bit loud and breezy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First meeting and trainer deployed</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/first_meeting_and_trainer_deployed/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 26 Feb 2025 22:03:50 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/first_meeting_and_trainer_deployed/</guid>
      <description>Glad to have the first re-kickoff meeting for the CO Rail game&amp;hellip; and I am still 100% glad to be doing the project&amp;hellip; Epically these days.
I will have to wake up for the meeting that starts at 7AM. The game will be designed to be able to incorporate different locations around the world&amp;hellip; and different cultures. I will have to work hard to keep the work progressing. Next, I got my bike trainer out of storage and literally set up next to my bed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Coaching and Engineering</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/coaching_and_engineering/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Feb 2025 18:21:26 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/coaching_and_engineering/</guid>
      <description>I am glad to find two things: Triathlon Coaches and Engineers.
The first one is pretty easy to understand as I train for Ironman Copenhagen, the second one is about the CO Rail game.
The Coach to make the plan (which I will commit and execute) for getting into shape and learning how to use nutrition to prevent bonks.
The Engineer will get the work from the design team and me and will get it built.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Clubs</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/clubs/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 21 Feb 2025 22:56:06 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/clubs/</guid>
      <description>I like clubs as they promote growth, community and meeting new people:
University affiliated clubs Exercise/workout clubs Air and space clubs Computer clubs Outdoor clubs Cold plunge clubs Language clubs Scandinavian culture clubs Writing clubs Alumni clubs Running clubs Supper clubs So its weird that I work for a night club.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>F_Strings</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/f_strings/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Feb 2025 21:30:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/f_strings/</guid>
      <description>I am going back though the Python course and so far I am re-learning a bit more&amp;hellip; but I just solved a question about F Strings, or Fancier Output Formatting. I accidentally did a concatenation, thinking it would be simpler, but Boots the AI said I should use a F String to avoid confusion.
Anyway, here&amp;rsquo;s to F Strings.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Train Stories</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/train_stories/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 17 Feb 2025 17:15:43 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/train_stories/</guid>
      <description>While at the Gym I saw a TV show about trains. After Googlting it, its called [Tracks Ahead](https://www.pbs.org/show/tracks-ahead
I am looking forward to watching it and seeying how they make stories.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Return of Python</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/return_of_python/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 14:23:35 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/return_of_python/</guid>
      <description>I just learned that I Can use return for many things, not just simple variables. I can do calculations, and boolean, function calls, and complex combinations.
I am glad to slowly going back into the Python course.
Taking it a bit slowly to fully learn everything. Also wanting to use what I learn in a actual small program. So that is different.
Only goal is just do a bit every day and ask the boot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snow dumping</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/snow_dumping/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 15 Feb 2025 11:38:03 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/snow_dumping/</guid>
      <description>Pure white snow flakes fall, Pillows laden all branches, What a site to see.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Games as tools</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/games_as_tools/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 14 Feb 2025 15:04:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/games_as_tools/</guid>
      <description>While running on the treadmill I was reading the book &amp;ldquo;Playing with reality&amp;rdquo; by Kelly Clancy. It goes though the history of games, and the related fields that games effect.
But the main thing that I get out of the book is this:
Games can change history. The Rail Game goal is to make passenger trains in Colorado popular and empower everyone to push for transportation. I can&amp;rsquo;t wait to also share cool info about local history in regards to trains.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Start of the game</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/start_of_the_game/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 12 Feb 2025 21:38:15 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/start_of_the_game/</guid>
      <description>I am really excited with the start of Phase 1 of the Rail Game.
I look forward to making stories, doing research and doing public outreach.
The outreach might include video, like interviews or live streams.
Also, yesterday when I started up Civ7, it crashed. I was a bit sad. Also, I feel with these big video games like Civ7 or Helldivers, or even Cyberpunk, I feel that they are really stressful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Saunagus</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/saunagus/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 19:45:47 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/saunagus/</guid>
      <description>I really liked the experience of essential oils in a Sauna in Denmark.
Its called Saunagus and I did it at marienlyst.dk.
I would really like to do it more often here. What I would need is
Approval from GH sauna. Times of the day to do it, maybe Wed, Sat? Essential oils. A fan. Sperilenia shots or something like that. Maybe a consultation from a Sanagus expert in Copenhagen. Relaxing spa music or access to the AV system and a ringing bowl or two.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Civilization Game Day</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/new_civilization_game_day/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 11 Feb 2025 08:29:04 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/new_civilization_game_day/</guid>
      <description>As a new Civ game is coming out today, I cant wait to play it.
I still like Civ 1, 2, 3 and 5.
I want to get cherry coke and chips queso. Maybe I do this on Friday so I can spend the whole day playing it. Just one more turn.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Re Starting Python learning</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/re-starting_python_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 09 Feb 2025 14:42:01 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/re-starting_python_learning/</guid>
      <description>I am starting from the beginning in Python on Boot.dev. I have been thinking a while that if I were to go further on Loops, I would get really lost.
So I am going to the start. I hope it clicks slightly more than last time. Maybe I should make a project whith what I am learning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More CCNA Study</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/more_ccna_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 08 Feb 2025 15:03:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/more_ccna_study/</guid>
      <description>I am plugging away in studying for the CCNA. I get the feeling though that this STP/RSTP and EtherChannel configuration is difficult.
I need to use the virtual Pearsons CCNA Simulator alot more. Logging into and out of switches and interfaces takes a bit of muscle memory.
I also need to re-study my Subnetting skills as I got it somewhat down, but I really need a re-fresher.
Basically, more study will be good.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Blueberries</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/blueberries/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 06 Feb 2025 23:40:17 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/blueberries/</guid>
      <description>How I like to eat them:
Snack FrozenSnack Frozen and in water as ice cubes Smoothie Bilberries (European wild blueberries) in Scandinavia soup. </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning and Study</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learning_and_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 05 Feb 2025 21:38:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learning_and_study/</guid>
      <description>Today I moved a switch and NVR, created a new VLAN for duplicating a new SSID and then did a ton of cable management.
I would say most of what I did was just from learning. The the VLAN and SSID could be considered something I studied for&amp;hellip; but I would say its about 15%.
So as I study for the CCNA, consider studying for the AZ-800 Administering Windows Server Hybrid Core Infrastructure and Boot.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CO Trains in the News</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/co_trains_in_the_news/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 04 Feb 2025 18:39:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/co_trains_in_the_news/</guid>
      <description>During this holding pattern with the funding of the UXUI, I keep seeing news articles in the news about passenger rail in CO.
I keep saving the news articles with the hope that they will be part of the story line of the game.
I also keep thinking about the different expansions of the games, to fill out the narrative of passenger rail in other countries. I think about Shinkansen in Japan and old mining town trains in Colorado.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Morning</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/morning/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 30 Jan 2025 07:46:28 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/morning/</guid>
      <description>Its around 7 AM in the morning&amp;hellip; and I am writing this instead of learning on Boot.dev.
I really want to start the practice of getting up early and doing code.
The Python loop section I am on got really hard, or I forgot what the core concept was&amp;hellip; so I have to go back and re-learn loops.
Or I wonder if I just go back to the start with Python.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Backyards</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/backyards/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 28 Jan 2025 18:37:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/backyards/</guid>
      <description>I think about backyards alot.
Whether its putting in a veggie garden or a organic pool, or both.
I dream about things that happen in backyards, sometimes they are bad dreams of tornado&amp;rsquo;s or zombies.
My dream backyard would have a veggie garden, a 25 yard organic pool to swim in, and a outdoor shower. I really want to grow things and be able to swim in the morning and evening without having chlorine and then take a shower on really hot days.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stoicness</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/stoicness/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Jan 2025 18:34:25 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/stoicness/</guid>
      <description>Not sure if its a word but going with it as a title.
I wanted to run commute this morning but didnt wake up early enough as my alarm was off.
I really wanted to run in the afternoon, but was so hungry as I didnt get lunch on time.
So now I have had dinner and did a bit of study and now going on a small run on treadmill.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Fitness Ramp-Up</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/fitness_ramp_up/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 Jan 2025 20:39:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/fitness_ramp_up/</guid>
      <description>Its really interesting to see Strava data from years ago.
I can see how I was performing in the phone app for a max of 2 years ago.
My goals this year is to get a solid base.
In previous years I did a ladder style treadmill running plan. Each week I increase millage. I think I have been doing 4ish mile last week. Need to increase it to 5 miles this week.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Obsolete_vs_Foundational</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/obsolete_vs_foundational/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 25 Jan 2025 14:40:54 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/obsolete_vs_foundational/</guid>
      <description>When studding for the CCNA, alot of the material is foundational stuff on how networks work. But then I am learning alout about Cisco products at the same time. I dont know if I will every use the stuff I learn about Cisco though. So I dont know if if its Obsolete stuff with the Cisco focused product, as I might just use Ubiquity tech.
Then when I play Civ3, I wonder if its a obsolete game (just like how new researched tech can make old tech obsolete in Civ).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quotes and Lyrics</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/quotes_and_lyrics/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 21 Jan 2025 18:53:39 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/quotes_and_lyrics/</guid>
      <description>I really cannot remmeber quotes and lyrics word for word.
The reason I think about this is I heard a good quote today.
Know thy enemy and know the outcome of 1,000 battles.
The quote was on a strava post and was about a barbell workout.
Otherwise I like running on the treadmill and listening to music with the lyrics displayed.
Keeps me occupied and keeps it going.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Room Colors and Streaming Stations</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/room_colors_and_streaming_stations/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 20:54:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/room_colors_and_streaming_stations/</guid>
      <description>Room colors and radio stations.
While these are not super related, I think about them alot.
The room colors I think about are a light green,light blue (or white) and a reddish color (or perhaps a golden aspen color). Another color pallet for a room would be the color of dried corn stocks, the dried red corn cob and yellow of dried corn seed.
I think these colors would be great in interror rooms of a straw bale house.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting Back to Study CCNA</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/getting_back_to_study_ccna/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 19 Jan 2025 15:23:29 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/getting_back_to_study_ccna/</guid>
      <description>So I am finally getting back to study CCNA, but I forgot that I was still on the STP and RSTP chapter.
Its so long.
I also cant help but think that companies Ubiquity and Unifi solution make studding this knowledge kinda redundant&amp;hellip; but I still want to continue the study as it gives me a foundational view of networking.
I also am thinking that it might change if I take the CCNA, as I really don&amp;rsquo;t need to right now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civ3 and Civ7</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/civ3_and_civ7/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 18 Jan 2025 22:51:05 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/civ3_and_civ7/</guid>
      <description>I have alot of mixed feelings.
I went down the rabbit hole of learning about Civ3 and I basically forgot how cool it was.
Its so different from Civ1 and Civ2, and in my brief time today playing it, it was really enjoyable. It fixes alot of what I don&amp;rsquo;t like about Civ1 (mainly how improvements to tiles requires so much work) and Civ2 (more debt and content and features).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pool Time</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/pool_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 15 Jan 2025 21:13:11 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/pool_time/</guid>
      <description>It has been a while since I last swam. Some things that I realized:
It was cold outside and when I first got in, but was manageable by the end. I need a swim cap. Not swimming means you loose it pretty quickly. I am going to try and not use fins. I am going to try and do pushups on the deck. I need jammers. I need more lotion and swim shampoo for after the swim.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>First day</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/first_day/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 13 Jan 2025 21:23:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/first_day/</guid>
      <description>First day at a new job. I will have worked at some of the biggest employers in the small town.
First day doing a full run commute, and weight training by doing 10 push-ups, 10 sit ups and 10 squats and then farmer carry two 45 pound kettlebell four times around this afternoon.
Still doing alot of other non-first day things like writing this post and study on Boot.Dev.
Also trying no to put too much stress into keeping the streak up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New Plan</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/new_plan/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 12 Jan 2025 15:01:30 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/new_plan/</guid>
      <description>Concept for a Retail Space: I envision a unique store that combines several passions:
Saysky Clothing: A curated selection of Saysky running apparel.
Coffee &amp;amp; Snacks: A cozy cafe serving high-quality coffee and light bites.
Scandi &amp;amp; Local Goods: Featuring a carefully chosen assortment of Scandinavian and locally-made products.
Unique Experiences: Nordic Connection: Showcase beautiful ceramics, drawing parallels between the limited-edition, seasonal designs and the exclusivity of Saysky. Educational Video Games: Host events and workshops related to educational gaming, potentially focusing on a series of games centered around Colorado (present, historical, futuristic).</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Exercise Loops</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/exercise_loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 10 Jan 2025 14:35:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/exercise_loops/</guid>
      <description>I am re-learning loops in Python on boot.dev and it was kinda hard. But I can use Boots to help me so that was nice.
I also often do the same loops while running. I know code and exercise are different but I am glad to be kinda boring.
I am also going to try and do the Daily Stoic 10 push-ups, 10 sit ups, 10 squats. Today at the gym I also did farmer carries and multiple rounds of different kinds of squats, sit ups and planks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Random writing</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/random_writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 09 Jan 2025 22:51:47 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/random_writing/</guid>
      <description>I just need to write a post for today to keep my Stoic journey up in writing.
So I am trying to think of something random to write about.
I am looking at my LED cancel, my smart speaker, a Danish flag, white water bottle, university coaster, phone charger holder and finally a blue pottery coorie home.
I think that sums me up pretty well. I could talk alot about each of the items, but this bedside table is exactly what I like to see when I go to sleep and wake up.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Civ 1 and Civ 2</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/civ_1_and_2/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 08 Jan 2025 15:52:01 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/civ_1_and_2/</guid>
      <description>I put Civ 1 and Civ 2 back on my surface pro.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know why, as I have Civ 1 on my Mac, but I just felt like I needed to play just one more turn.
I don&amp;rsquo;t know why I think about it so much. I remember playing it on a computer in the basement and the music and soundtrack, and the history I was learning by playing each Civ.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stoic Year</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/stoic_year/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 07 Jan 2025 15:53:00 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/stoic_year/</guid>
      <description>Some things I am looking forward to.
Marathons and Ironman in Scandianiva Learning Danish Applying Daily Stoic lessons Working on side projects I am just really excited to be re-focuing on these and having a exciting year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gone</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/gone/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 03 Jan 2025 22:12:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/gone/</guid>
      <description>She is gone. It was really nice meeting all her friends. Today coincided with the task of learning Memento Mori, &amp;ldquo;Remember we are mortal.&amp;rdquo;
Its actually a deliberate practice to know that we could be gone at any moment and that we should be energized by urgency to live life more fully. To be more intentional, more urgent and more appreciative of life.
&amp;ldquo;Love more deeply, create more boldly, forgive more quickly, and live more fully.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Favorite Photos</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/favorite_photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 30 Dec 2024 17:49:36 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/favorite_photos/</guid>
      <description>Looking at a old hard drive with tons of photos is remarkable.
Its hard to comprehend just how many photos and places and moments there are.
And yet we can remember them in our mind relatively effortlessly.
Its hard to choose favorites from so many.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Remarks</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/remarks/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Dec 2024 22:18:08 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/remarks/</guid>
      <description>First draft:
I want to share some of the things I have learned from someone.
How to write cursive. She had amazing handwriting, and from her practicing with me the curisve letters I still write some of them from her form. Jokes. She had a great way of telling jokes. Laughing. She wanted to see you laugh, which made her laugh more and made me laugh more. Travel. She traveled with groups and would not pass up the opportunity to visit places.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Memories</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/memories/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Dec 2024 23:27:49 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/memories/</guid>
      <description>In thinking of what to write, a friend offered a danish pastry to me. I had remembered that I talked to my grandma yesterday and we talked about how I would be going back to Denmark to run. I miss my grandma.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>New routine</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/new_routine/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Dec 2024 15:56:51 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/new_routine/</guid>
      <description>I am really glad to start a new routine. There are actually three:
Fitness Job Stoic New Year New You 2025 </description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Completing games</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/completing_games/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Dec 2024 18:14:01 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/completing_games/</guid>
      <description>I pretty much finished the main plot line of a video game last night.
This is the second game that I have finished the main plot line, and in both cases I was primarly motovated by gaining access to the highest power level.
So perhaps that is a good thing to learn from when I am thinking about the Colorado Rail Game.
If I were to have a winning scenerio as having the most &amp;ldquo;power&amp;rdquo; or having the ability to travel in the train with a &amp;ldquo;first class&amp;rdquo; fare, that might be motovating for people to play the game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>More grep</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/more_grep/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:55:23 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/more_grep/</guid>
      <description>I needed to remember how to find a grep command that I used in the past so I did a Ctrl + r and then typed in grep and I found I had used grep -rco &amp;quot;searchterm&amp;quot; and then whaterver I searched for.
So I have to be in the directory that all the files I need to search in are in, which is a bit of a hassle, but its quick and shows me count of how many occurances the word is in each file.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Flowers and photos</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/flowers_and_photos/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Dec 2024 18:05:52 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/flowers_and_photos/</guid>
      <description>I am really looking forward to two purchases I recently made.
Both have been on my mind for a while.
First is a salt-shaker like canisters that have different kind of seeds in them and other is a large digital picture frame.
I really hope the shaker can spread a ton of flowers in the spring.
And I like the big format of the photo frame, and it will be fun to see photos more regularly.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold run</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cold_run/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 05 Dec 2024 18:49:50 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cold_run/</guid>
      <description>I said that I would just run around the park. Thats it. Its not even a mile.
I started running up a small narrow uphill. Half way around a curve there was a walker slowing moving up the path. So I had to walk half the uphill.
Next I decided to head downhill and around. This is when the first sharp bite of cold happened. Luckily I had a hat but I did not have any gloves.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Protein shakes</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/protein_shakes/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 04 Dec 2024 17:39:43 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/protein_shakes/</guid>
      <description>After I am done at work I go do a workout or do some study.
I am usually pretty hungry as it could be around 4-6 pm when I do this.
So I have enjoyed drinking a 325 ML dark chocolate protien shae with 20g protein. It fills me up and makes me study better.
Also cheap at less than $5.00 and healthier than other sports drinks.
Would recommend with a apple or banana or beef jerky.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Audio</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/audio/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 03 Dec 2024 20:31:50 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/audio/</guid>
      <description>I have been going back and forth about getting a smart speaker. I miss music in the morning, and miss it in the evening. So I checked again and its out of stock.
I have no regrets in buying nice earbuds. Love noise canceling and music when running.
I would love to have a MP3 player for the pool. Havent really hunted for a deal on those.
I also like my speakers in my car, but would love to upgrade those with a better subwoofer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Books from the cloud</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/books_from_the_cloud/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 02 Dec 2024 18:06:24 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/books_from_the_cloud/</guid>
      <description>I am really impressed with having the entire written collection of books on early accessible from any device.
This weekend I purchased Stillness is the Key by Ryan Holiday and rented from the public library when Things Don&amp;rsquo;t Go Your Way by Haemin Sunmin. Within seconds I had them on my phone, and tens of seconds I had them on my Kindle.
Its ironic that I Am also still studying networking in the CCNA as those technologies enabled me getting those book so fast.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VLANs</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/vlans/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Nov 2024 11:44:15 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/vlans/</guid>
      <description>Finally getting started in learning about VLANs and how to create them.
It reminds me a bit about socal networking. I am really glad that I am studing these fundamental concepts as everything in IT rests on networking.
I wonder if I can use the same framework to think of side projects, and how VLANs can help shape the way these projects get finished faster.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Debugging</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/debugging/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Nov 2024 22:42:17 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/debugging/</guid>
      <description>Today I didn&amp;rsquo;t feel motivated to get my laptop opened at 10:40 at night and try and learn some python. I had a long day and it was frustrating troubleshooting.
So I started the module on debugging.
But what I learned is that I can use the same logic in debugging with larger tech issues at work. The basic method is:
Attempted to solve it yourself first Use print() statements to understand what your code is actually doing Test different approaches Identify the specific part that&amp;rsquo;s confusing you</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Back at skiing</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/back_at_skiing/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 24 Nov 2024 13:06:19 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/back_at_skiing/</guid>
      <description>I cant believe I haven&amp;rsquo;t skied for so long. I am glad I was able to again, but also I dont think I missed it so much.
Also I am back at learning networking. I am really glad to be starting it again but also these two textbooks are huge. I cant wait to finish them.
I also forgot how to do subnetting and that will need to re-learn it a certain amount.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cold Swim</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cold_swim/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 19 Nov 2024 20:23:48 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cold_swim/</guid>
      <description>Man I didn&amp;rsquo;t want to swim the 1600, but I did. I usually surface at 300, then 500 then 700&amp;hellip;. then I power though to 1000, then I look at 1300 and then 1570 &amp;hellip;. and then finally my 1600.
Then i&amp;rsquo;m out of the pool and feeling really good that I swam that far.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Quick bus ride</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/quick_bus_ride/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Nov 2024 15:09:35 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/quick_bus_ride/</guid>
      <description>Glad that I can take a bus pretty much any time to and from the mountains.
There is something like 20 buses going to Union Station. Which is great as none are usually totally full.
Otherwise would love if there as 20 passenger trains going to and from,so we wouldn&amp;rsquo;t have to rely on the highway being closed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Strawbale walls</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/strawbale_walls/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 14 Nov 2024 20:40:03 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/strawbale_walls/</guid>
      <description>I would do anything for a straw bale house. Yesterday I was looking at a Australian company that has prefab straw walls, and they look thinner than Modcell SIPS.
The main thing I want is better insulation, and should prevention.
I want to be warm/cold and not hear a thing.
I keep on thinking of two kinds of buildings&amp;hellip; that would be fun to have in two different locations.
One kind like a giant square with a central courtyard, like a riad with a Andalusian patio or a ancient roman domus.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Turkey</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/turkey/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Nov 2024 19:13:02 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/turkey/</guid>
      <description>Cant believe were already past Halloween and onto Thanksgiving.
I am not looking forward to the rest of cold and frigid winter.
The main thing I don&amp;rsquo;t like about winter is waiting for my car to defrost. Taking precious time to scrape it and then crank up the heat by using up gas and battery life.
I also don&amp;rsquo;t like slipping everywhere.
If I could, I would love to celebrate all these &amp;ldquo;winter&amp;rdquo; holidays and feasts some place a bit warmer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Chapters and Loops</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/chapters_and_loops/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Nov 2024 19:11:46 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/chapters_and_loops/</guid>
      <description>At first I was thinking of writing about the CCNA textbooks which I am slowly getting though and how I run loops (slowly) around a park.
For the CCNA textbooks, I cant help to think how long its taken for me to get to this point.
I have been on Github for 13 years, which I made sure by doing math in the command line: expr 2024 - 2011
So its just taking me a long time, and feels like I am in a loop of learning and runnnig.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>From Chromebook to Debian to PopOS</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/from_chromebook_to_debian_to_popos/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:54:17 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/from_chromebook_to_debian_to_popos/</guid>
      <description>I have a old Dell laptop that I put ChromeOS Flex on. After using it for half a year, I finally thought that I needed full Linux. I use another old dell with Fedora and I3WM and I really liked that experience, but that laptop has issues with its speaker and the screen is small.
So I finally decided to go full Linux and remove ChromeOS with Debian. However after a couple attempts with etching Debian to my USB, I gave up on Debian installer.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gaming and PDFs</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/gaming_and_pdfs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Nov 2024 09:44:39 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/gaming_and_pdfs/</guid>
      <description>I want to write about how there are really simple UI indi games out (like the game Turmoil) there right now and I am really excited by how they look and how easy it is to interact with them and use your imagination.
Like in &amp;rsquo;90s video games, the pixel art left alot to the imagination and I think that is a good thing.
The second thing is that I get PDF newsletters in email from groups supporting passenger rail.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Steel Drum</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/steel_drum/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 07 Nov 2024 21:02:56 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/steel_drum/</guid>
      <description>Yup, steel drum might be the most happy sounding instrument.
Makes me feel happy and it literally cannot make someone sad.
It if I were to compare it to other instruments, perhaps the bongos or xylophone are almost as happy sounding.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sweaters</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sweaters/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 06 Nov 2024 19:18:53 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sweaters/</guid>
      <description>Thoughts on them:
I have too many of them. I don&amp;rsquo;t want them to get damaged so I don&amp;rsquo;t ware them enough. They are too thick and hot I don&amp;rsquo;t want to wear something that is itchy They remind me of Scotland. I like how they keep me warm I am getting ready for sweater weather.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long run</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/long_run/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 03 Nov 2024 16:52:43 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/long_run/</guid>
      <description>The timezone changed with fall back and its getting dark. I don&amp;rsquo;t know if I am really ready for winter.
I did probably the last warm long run here till next spring. This run was hard, I went really slowly, running though the golf course and up the pass a bit. The cold weather helped and my having hydration with mix made me feel great.
I also cant wait for working on some projects next year.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Questions and study</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/questions_and_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Oct 2024 18:35:05 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/questions_and_study/</guid>
      <description>In a meeting today I apologised for the emails asking for more clarification and asking questions. I was told it was better to ask questions than not.
I am in the deep end of networking study for the CCNA and I just bought a book that I have no idea about, cybersecurity.
But I am going to ask the questions anyway and power though the awkward parts of learning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Rocks and trains</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/rocks_and_trains/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 27 Oct 2024 11:49:56 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/rocks_and_trains/</guid>
      <description>It seems like Colorado&amp;rsquo;s history of trains is also about the geology and rocks of Colorado.
The mountains are so tall, the valleys are so narrow, and the rocks are so hard.
Its hard to fathom just how much effort it was moving all the rocks
Even modern earth moving methods, are just shinny and newer versions of what dynamite, pick axes and leveraging steel accomplished.
Still the same from the past are the large amounts of money and energy these massive undertakings needed to focused.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Ready made</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/ready_made/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 26 Oct 2024 21:27:51 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/ready_made/</guid>
      <description>Love whole foods.
So when I end up in a whole foods, I buy a bunch of random, non food stuff. But often what I get and most look forard to, are ready made items near the bakery, salad bar and pre-made entrees and sides.
I sometimes open my Mad Fit app and look up meals for inspiration.
I then think of entrees I have not had, like spicy madras curry, and get those spacial treat meals that differ than what I normally eat.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Snow on peaks</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/snow_on_peaks/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 25 Oct 2024 16:22:54 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/snow_on_peaks/</guid>
      <description>As I look across reservoir &amp;ldquo;lake&amp;rdquo; Dillon, I see above treeline snow. Its both great to see but ominous to know that winter is coming.
Very relieved to have a plan on the video game as well. However I will have to increase the project cost and scope with the crowdfunding campaign.
So with excitement of front page Vail Daily articles about western slope passenger rail lines, and how the video game will help those dreams, I know it will be a long winter and spring is far off.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Project initiation phase</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/project_initiation_phase/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 22 Oct 2024 21:59:10 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/project_initiation_phase/</guid>
      <description>While swimming I thought about three things:
Rail game Triathlon plan Swimming Rail game I have to re-plan the project due to cost.
There will be a discovery phase and then a development phase. The discovery phase will cost as much as I thought the whole project would cost. Then I have no idea on the development phase.
I can pay for the discovery phase, which will then give me enough content to then go live with crowdfunding, YouTube and merch.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Comet and aspen leaves</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/comet_and_aspen_leaves/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 15 Oct 2024 21:24:32 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/comet_and_aspen_leaves/</guid>
      <description>Seeing a comet is really a rare joy. Since there is one up right now, and it wont be visible for another 80,000 years or if ever, it really made makes me think of those timelines which are so hard to understand and grasp. A space.com article said it is making its &amp;ldquo;first and last appearance.&amp;rdquo;
The brief nature of the comet for us on earth made me think of all the cool aspen leaves that I have seen on the ground this fall.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swim Run Study</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/swim_run_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 14 Oct 2024 18:43:40 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/swim_run_study/</guid>
      <description>The plan was to run to the pool and then swim, but then it started to look rainy. By the time I made it in the pool it was starting to rain.
I was glad to not be running in the rain.
What you might not know is if its raining over a large body of water, each rain droplets bounce upward in the pool as the surface tension of water breaks gravity.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Starship and Network Simulator</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/starship_and_network_simulator/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 13 Oct 2024 18:14:52 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/starship_and_network_simulator/</guid>
      <description>Woke up really early on a Sunday by my alarm which somehow was still set from a early morning race. Luckily this was launch day and my overall impression of the launch was that I am really surprised that the Booster was caught by the chopsticks. I was also surprised that the Starship still had a bit of tile issues near the flap.
Later in the day I re-started my learning for the CCNA with a change, from studying subnetting to using the network simulator to start learning how to interact with routers and switches.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advocacy</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/advocacy/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 11 Oct 2024 16:53:07 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/advocacy/</guid>
      <description>Really happy when plans come together. Its been many months since we first started to scope out the Colorado Rail game.
Today was the first meeting with the project manager who is helping guide the project. What struck me was how much research he did to understand the game. From comparing the game to others, to figuring out what the color scheme is, to asking who the target audience is to understanding the flow of the game and the attractions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Boot.dev vs Coursera</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/boot.dev_vs_coursera/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 10 Oct 2024 20:46:50 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/boot.dev_vs_coursera/</guid>
      <description>When I think about online study I often think of Coursera, However, I now thint its a bit too passive. I need to be using what I learn.
So I looked at my Coursera courses and didn&amp;rsquo;t see anything except a TCPIP course. I wanted to do something a bit different tonight so I logged back into my Boot.Dev course and click start over on Python.
For right now I want interactive and practical.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Practice exams</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/practice_exams/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 09 Oct 2024 17:52:08 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/practice_exams/</guid>
      <description>In studding for the CCNA, I am using a host of resources. Simulator software, real Cisco hardware, textbooks and online exams.
I am trying to put a full court press in learning the materials. I am glad I finished my IP Subnetting online course but now when I am turning to the textbooks, I am finding that I have so many other resources.
One such resource is the PTP practice exam, as I just took about 10 questions and only got one correct.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Old course</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/old_course/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 08 Oct 2024 19:51:10 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/old_course/</guid>
      <description>It was really nice to see a old course I made. It had a 4.2 star rating and had over 3000 students signed up.
I had kinda forgotten about it.
As I work on the video game, I am looking forward to having users and getting it online for people to learn about history, politics and transportation.
I also look forward for people supporting the work and giving feedback. I hope the game will be much more interactive than the online course in making updates.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>VLSM</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/vlsm/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 07 Oct 2024 21:47:26 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/vlsm/</guid>
      <description>As I learn more about networking, I really need to apply it. I have some hardware to use to learn how to do it but I also have some software that can emulate networks.
Cant wait to also jump back into my books for the CCNA from this side course on subnetting that I figured would be a great resource to learn some of the hardest things in networking.
It should give me a great foundation to understand networks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I3 on a laptop</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/i3_on_a_laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 02 Oct 2024 19:23:55 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/i3_on_a_laptop/</guid>
      <description>I really enjoy using i3 to quickly go back and forth between workspaces, applications and windows.
For Firefox I use Vimium shortcuts and this is super helpful pausing and playing videos for online learning.
I sometimes need a calculator so I ctrl and enter to search for calculator and then I use the i3 keybindings to resize it between my other windows of online learning and neovim for taking notes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Stories and storytelling</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/stories_and_storytelling/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 29 Sep 2024 21:31:52 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/stories_and_storytelling/</guid>
      <description>After the creative writing meetup, I was interested in what constitutes a story and who is the storyteller. I originally joined just to become a better writer, but it&amp;rsquo;s quickly becoming a way to be a better storyteller.
When we first read or learn a story, we automatically become storytellers by retelling it. This retelling is important, as our version will probably be different from the original story.
If a person changes the story to deceive, it might be a form of manipulation.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Creative writing</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/creative_writing/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 26 Sep 2024 23:24:27 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/creative_writing/</guid>
      <description>Last night was a fanatic night talking and sharing writing.
I just really liked it and i am glad I made it to the event.
I will try and o more creative writing to became a better writer.
I cant wait fr the video game to help me write out characters for the game.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Run and calculate</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/run_and_calculate/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 24 Sep 2024 23:03:09 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/run_and_calculate/</guid>
      <description>I just found out that computer calculator in Fedora &amp;ldquo;gnome_calculator&amp;rdquo; can do exponents by holding down the Ctrl key and typing out the exponent you want.
This was an amazing breakthough for me and why I am glad I decided to study at 11pm at night.
Also I am glad to have gone on a difficult run, one that I really wanted to push, and that I saw alot of animals, alot of golden aspen and alot of sunset.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swim and steam room</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/swim_and_steam_room/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 23 Sep 2024 20:21:29 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/swim_and_steam_room/</guid>
      <description>Nice to have a routine of doing 1500 yards in the pool and then use the steam room for a bit.
While swimming I was thinking of doing push-ups, 25 per 50 yards, and then up to 100. But I decided to do some laps with head out of water in a lifeguard style swim that so you can spot the person needing help.
I really want to have a training plan though as I have kinda plateaued with ideas.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Two days off</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/two_days_off/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 22 Sep 2024 19:01:41 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/two_days_off/</guid>
      <description>Funny to have two days off of study and exercise.
By the third day I am itching to study and go for a run/swim/bike.
I am now catching up and doing a bit of study before going to bed.
I feel a bit rusty in starting up finding numbers of subnets and I wish I had gone for a long swim this weekend.
Also if I were to list my hobbies I guess it would be:</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Old laptop for study</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/old_laptop_for_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 18 Sep 2024 21:58:10 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/old_laptop_for_study/</guid>
      <description>Its a really old Dell laptop that doesnt have much RAM or Memory but Fedora with i3 works amazing.
I have Firefox, Tmux and perhaps a calculator if I am doing subnetting on the screen.
The speakers are not the best, the battery maybe lasts for almost 3 hours and the trackpad is just bad, but its lightweight, the keyboard feels good and the backlight keys still works.
Overall I am super happy to have this old laptop for study as it also keeps me focused on the main task of study and getting better with Tmux, neovim, linux and i3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>CPH goals</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cph_goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 08:32:29 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cph_goals/</guid>
      <description>I am really stoked to be doing two races in CPH. My goals are two part.
Spend more time in CPH and hopefully find a job/opportunity. Have two big races to structure my life around and also have a regime for training over the winter. There are alot of spin off goals and things that will occure with the two above goals.
Learn Danish Try and find a new job Travel around more in Denmark.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Next year goals</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/next_year_goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Sep 2024 17:22:38 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/next_year_goals/</guid>
      <description>2025 is starting to shape up, but also we have some hopes for the next year.
Some athletic goals are:
Run Marathons in Copenhagen and Helsinki Do Ironman Copenhagen Learn skate sking more and more skinning up. Learning goals:
CCNA Finish some other coursera courses and boot.dev Another trade school cert? Work goals:
Be my own boss. Do more YouTube. Use certs in work. Life goals:
Finish Rail game. More Europe.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sunflower and bulbs</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sunflower_and_bulbs/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 14 Sep 2024 15:27:39 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sunflower_and_bulbs/</guid>
      <description>I like seeing sunflower seeds that grow into big sunflowers and annual bulbs grow into hundreds of flowers.
Its starting to be that time of year I see bulbs on sale and thing about what I can grow next year.
Its also that time of year Coursera renews and I think of what courses I want to learn.
I am also looking into a cyber cert to reinforce my networking knoweldge.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Happy with online study</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/happy_with_online_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 11 Sep 2024 08:30:49 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/happy_with_online_study/</guid>
      <description>I am so glad I am having some success with online study.
Getting test problems correct is really nice for a change.
I made a ton of mistakes, but that is okay.
Again, I am so glad I have switched to CCNA from Network+. Things are just clicking alot better.
But I am wanting to go back to boot.dev and continue my coding leaerning.
Just glad to have some happiness with my studies.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Run Commute and Study</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/run_commute_and_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 09 Sep 2024 08:54:57 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/run_commute_and_study/</guid>
      <description>Glad to have a new rutine in run commute, take a shower, eat cusuant and have latte and then do some online study.
I did some subnetting practice problems and got some wrong answers. But I am learning and its good practice. Also glad to see people.
Run commute is not super long but its not easy to wake up and do it as it was kinda chilly. I am also glad to get steps in and get some sunlight in.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Subnets and projects</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/subnets_and_projects/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 07 Sep 2024 20:49:29 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/subnets_and_projects/</guid>
      <description>While I study subnets, I cant help but think about other projects at work.
I still remember wanting to have a template that can be used for any project, great or small.
The template would be like a pager and then I would fill it out if anybody would ask for something.
I also think back to my slide writing course and how I wish I had finished it and taken more notes.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Early Morning Study</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/early_morning_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 06 Sep 2024 08:57:56 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/early_morning_study/</guid>
      <description>I have a new time planning idea. I wake up early and run commute to cafe, get a drink like a iced latte and a pastry like a chocolate croissant and then I fire up my computer and do a bit of CCNA study.
This helps a couple ways.
I can get a exercise done I get study in I feel accomplished with learning something new I get a coffee I can shower at the coworking place It sets me up for a great day So I cant wait to start to do this more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Long weekend goals</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/long_weekend_goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Aug 2024 21:04:54 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/long_weekend_goals/</guid>
      <description>With Labor day coming up, I have a big backlog of things to work on.
Work on game. Specifically hand over the UX workflow to the dev team. Learn more CCNA. Get Packet Tracer app up and play around. Learn more Go. Do a bit of Tableau. Do YouTube video of Straw Bale House project. Do YouTube video of game development. Also I want to do some other things.
Plan Trip to Finland/Estonia See if I should register for Ironman Copenhagen Do lots of running.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Excited to learn more</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/excited_to_learn_more/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 22 Aug 2024 22:37:31 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/excited_to_learn_more/</guid>
      <description>Today I learned that a Network tech coworker passed his CCNA. In the last couple of weeks and days I too have been studying the CCNA and I really like to see someone I know pass it.
Basically I also purchased a video course on IP Subnetting, so I really am glad to have books, videos, Cisco Packet Tracer software and now a coworker to tap into for my learning.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planning</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/planning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 21 Aug 2024 14:04:48 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/planning/</guid>
      <description>Been thinking about planning lately.
I need alot of planning. With projects like the video game, straw bale house and YouTube content creation for both of those projects, and other goals with my online courses.
I am now trying to plan other things and I realized I have not saved enough to include them in any kind of timeline.
Like standing behind the finish line vs right in front of it, planning is really important.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Homelab for learning</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/homelab_for_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 07 Aug 2024 19:42:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/homelab_for_learning/</guid>
      <description>I finally have enough old equipment to start a homelab. Some of it includes
Old WAPs Network switches Cloudcore router Firewall Fiber and SFPs Old micro desktops Possible old working server What I have for plans is to create this homelab and then somehow set up a way to remotely log into it. But I really have no idea how to do this right now.
Also I don&amp;rsquo;t know where it should be placed&amp;hellip; and where a good spot would be for it to live.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn Search and Select in Bash History</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learned_bash_history/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jul 2024 19:56:03 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learned_bash_history/</guid>
      <description>I finally learned how to write out a particular line in history.
I can never remember the IP address o log into a VPS via SSH. So I have to rely on typing history and then finding where I had last typed it and then copy and pasting the input into the new bash line.
This all is a pain. So I finally Googled something like search bash history and select input and found a forum post where the person said CMD + R.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slow Stream</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/slow_stream/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 29 Jul 2024 14:11:02 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/slow_stream/</guid>
      <description>I really like slow moving streams. I was walking next to Gore Creek and watched people on inter tubes float down the river. It was so hot and I wish I could sit in a inter tube.
But also I like the way they sound. Quiet stream noises make me want to go to sleep.
So one project I really want to do as I have been thinking about it for so long is taking my camera and lav audio mics up on the mountain in quiet areas and recording stream and wind sounds.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Planting Trees</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/planting_trees/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Jul 2024 15:10:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/planting_trees/</guid>
      <description>I watched a YouTube about how to plat trees for growing a forest. there were two methods. The regular approach is to just plant a some trees without much thought. The second thought is to use a method called the Miyawaki method.
This is to first improve the soil if needed. Then plant native trees and plants and as many different ones as possibly, and as closely together so there is more competition between the young trees.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Games and Scotland</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/video_games_and_scotland/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 23 Jul 2024 21:51:22 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/video_games_and_scotland/</guid>
      <description>I have really enjoyed playing one video game on the steam deck&amp;hellip; and its Hogwarts Legacy.
Not only is it fun to run around the world of Harry Potter, and be filled with nostalgia, but also it reminds me of Scotland and Edinburgh.
When I lived there it was so cold at night and dark&amp;hellip; but there were bits of it being brilliant.
Some things I miss are pubs, running around the city and how cozy things were.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Straw camp</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/straw_camp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 22 Jul 2024 21:42:45 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/straw_camp/</guid>
      <description>Well I survived. Glad I did not get injured and glad I signed up.
Camping in the car for 7 days was not as fun by the end, but I really did enjoy it.
Some things I learned:
Wear PPE, and buy the cool helmet as its better than getting a hammer on your head. Bring a solar panel as you never know if you will need to charge up a phone more.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video Game Music</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/video_game_music/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 11 Jul 2024 22:26:49 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/video_game_music/</guid>
      <description>I really like my video game music. Whether it was Civ 1 or 2 or later or Doom soundtrack or newer games, its just wonderful.
I often listen to it when working out and I sometimes think people don&amp;rsquo;t often listen to this great music as they do not play any games.
I also like listening to DR.DK/LYD and SR.SE and used to listen to BNN.FM and ShonanBeachFM.
Otherwise I just love it and am so glad there are such great songs out there.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Straw next week</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/straw_next_week/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 10 Jul 2024 21:47:26 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/straw_next_week/</guid>
      <description>I am really looking forward to a straw bale work camp next week where 30 or so volunteers will help fill in the insulation of between the frames with straw.
I am just so happy that I signed up for this so long ago.
I think I am more happy in that I am doing things I want to do and going after dreams and things that I want to go after.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Cross roads</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cross_roads/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Jul 2024 11:00:10 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/cross_roads/</guid>
      <description>Well in getting back to study, I am now wondering whether to continue with Network+ or go with CCNA.
Main reasons for this is that I feel the CCNA is a bit easier to learn. The study materials just make more sense.
Also, I am not liking the CompTia Network Plus study materials but rather CCNA by Wendell Odom.
A couple more cross roads are:
Buy mountain bike or continue with road bike.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Professional development price</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/professional_development_price/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 05 Jul 2024 20:42:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/professional_development_price/</guid>
      <description>I re-upped with Testout and paid for all their course cataloge. Not only is Network+ top course but ohers like Linux, Cyber, and Hybrid Server.
I am glad I signed up even though if feels expensive.
I am also glad to be writing this post on a steam deck. just need a better keyboard as the shift button is so small on the right.
I should be sure to take the cert tests, but I am glad to be a life long learner.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Everyday habits</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/everyday_habits/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 25 Jun 2024 20:05:19 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/everyday_habits/</guid>
      <description>Sitting on the poach and listening to Danish Radio&amp;rsquo;s classical music channel. I am thinking about white clouds in the sky and how the sun is setting and that I have not just looked up into the sky watched clouds move. I am really glad I purchased while in Heathrow the book on &amp;ldquo;The Daily Stoic&amp;rdquo; which has 365 lessons. I read alot of it on the plane and also coded alot of go on the plane and talked to someone who was a volunteer wild land firefighter.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Action items for game dev</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/action_items_for_game_dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 19 Jun 2024 07:20:05 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/action_items_for_game_dev/</guid>
      <description>In making a game its good to have a active PM. She thought I would benefit from having a UX expert help in the discussion to give me action items:
make a strait forward scenario that shows the game mechanic. Whether that is in sketches, frames, power points. describe in more detail the mini game. share free resources where to get images so we can create art. So now I have alot of homework to do, but I feel good as I understand the direction better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Five week project</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/five_week_project/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 16 Jun 2024 19:44:23 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/five_week_project/</guid>
      <description>I have not updated the blog due to a work project that has taken now 5 weeks.
Some of the project management lessons I have learned:
Scope out projects better&amp;hellip;. espically the fundamental truthes that the projects presume. Make sure you have enough people for projects. If initial people are not enough, then it will be a problem. If there is a problem. Stop and get attention to the situation. Other things I learned personally.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Other goals</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/other_goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 26 May 2024 15:41:15 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/other_goals/</guid>
      <description>I normally write about the big goals I have but some smaller goals are:
Learn how to do pull ups. Read more about stoic philosophy in my new book. Bike out to Parker and go to Fidd ka. Start seeds. Sign up for marathons next year. Go see a Starship launch Try and do more boot.dev and Head First Go book. Attend more open air events this summer. Learn how to play golf, tennis, pickle ball.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Post Vacation</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/post_vacation/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 17 May 2024 17:44:35 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/post_vacation/</guid>
      <description>Well I am back from vacation and totally didnt work on anything via a computer but rather tried to be in the moment and take things in. Some goals for next couple weeks:
Perhaps sign up for a instructor run Network+ course&amp;hellip; Do the UX/UI of the game. Do more online stuff like make a merch store for the game. I am looking forward to a straw bale workshop that I signed up for, but need to make a youtube channel and make some videos to then start up Coorie Home again.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Madrid_is_done</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/madrid_is_done/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 28 Apr 2024 13:21:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/madrid_is_done/</guid>
      <description>I am too tired to write a post, going to bed.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting back to backend dev</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/getting_back_to_backend_dev/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 17 Apr 2024 22:08:16 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/getting_back_to_backend_dev/</guid>
      <description>I am taking a break from Python&amp;hellip; for some reason its hard&amp;hellip; and I am skipping to learn my command line.
I am glad I am getting better at grep and file paths like Absolute vs Relative.
I think these short breaks are good but I also feel bad that I am avoiding python&amp;hellip; as I eventually want to start GO. Also I forget that after Python I will then start to learn JavaScript&amp;hellip;</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Vacation study</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/vacation_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 15 Apr 2024 21:50:54 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/vacation_study/</guid>
      <description>Thinking of what I will do over vacation time and when not running and traveling. Some things:
online studies. the game. YouTube Some things that are not so work related are:
Pools and swim more Yoga classes Fitness classes Bike ride in Copenhagen Go to a cooking class Otherwise, it will be busy.
Also, I am looking forward to just working on things that I want to work on and getting Jira items out of the way.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Spring is here</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/spring_is_here/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Apr 2024 20:58:31 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/spring_is_here/</guid>
      <description>I have not been studying and I have not been working on any project as I have been focusing on pretty much work and running.
I feel like I am cramming for a test in getting ready for the marathons. I wish I had started running a bit earlier this year and traing like in the last blog post with incrimental daily runs.
Otherwise I feel like I am pretty fit and will just survive marathons at lower altitude.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Study Hope</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/study_hope/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Apr 2024 18:55:37 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/study_hope/</guid>
      <description>After my hour of study Network+ I am starting to feel a bit confident.
I think I might be able to study it all and pass the exam.
I do want to go back and take exact steps and notes for subnetting. As well as do more with TCPIP and OSI model.
If I can get those down and memorized I will have a huge shot of actually passing.
I am looking forward to not having to study for this exam, and being more confident in general networking.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>How to train for marathons</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/how_to_train_for_marathons/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 07 Apr 2024 21:11:25 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/how_to_train_for_marathons/</guid>
      <description>I forgot how to train for a marathons, so I looked up my Strava history.
Just like I forgot how to replace all occurrences of _ on a line or document in vim&amp;hellip; so I just looked it up and its :%s/str1/str2/g with the g option if you want to replace all instances globally.
Back in the day when I did not know how to run long distances I used a book The Non-Runner&amp;rsquo;s Marathon Trainer by David A.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Slow Jog Slow Learning</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/slow_jog_slow_learning/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Apr 2024 12:02:52 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/slow_jog_slow_learning/</guid>
      <description>I went running on the treadmill again to get ready for the marathons and what struck me was how boring it was. I was constantly looking at my phone and changing music.
So I thought I should use a ipad to study my courses on Coursera. So after setting up Bluetooth headphones I was able to study TCP/IP and Hotel Financials course. It was great. I was going pretty slow and it made my ipad to have 75% battery, but after two hours I had done alot of study.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyperloop and trains</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/hyperloop_and_trains/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Apr 2024 20:50:24 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/hyperloop_and_trains/</guid>
      <description>Recently I have seen alot of positive updates regarding hyperloops and trains.
Specifically, hyperloop test track updates in Europe and Colorado and passenger rail plans in Colorado.
For hyperloop, Hardt Hyperloop and the European Hyperloop Center are completing their test track. I would love to see this in person. Also Swiss Pod is starting their test track in Pueblo Colorado at the PuebloPlex train testing facility. I too would love to visit this and support this.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>I3 and studies</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/i3_and_studies/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 02 Apr 2024 22:53:13 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/i3_and_studies/</guid>
      <description>I have enjoyed using my old laptop with Fedora and using i3 as my window manager.
I definitely forgot a lot but having the computer really do only so much helps me focus more so I don&amp;rsquo;t get distracted.
Also the battery lasts longer as I just have Firefox and my terminal open.
In Firefox I have added the extension called Vimium so I can navigate faster witout using the mouse.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Building off of layers</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/building_off_of_layers/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Apr 2024 22:09:15 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/building_off_of_layers/</guid>
      <description>In studding the OSI model layers, I am reminded of straw bale construction and plastering in layers. I am re-learning from my notes for the Network+ exam and it appears to make more sense this second time around. I also cant wait to re-learn straw bale construction and plastering. I think this second hands on workshop will be great.
Speaking of relearning, I am enjoying Fedora 39 on by Dell laptop using i3.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning tech skills</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learning_tech_skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 28 Mar 2024 21:14:13 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learning_tech_skills/</guid>
      <description>A lot of what I do is learn abstractly about tech and but then in the field have to remember how to use it.
For example, I have been learning about switches and ports, but had to remember quickly the stuff about switches to be able to re-learn how to find ports on a NVR.
I now know how to find video feeds from the NVR after having more time to take time and get familiar with the NVR.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hour Study Time</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/hour_study_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Mar 2024 16:05:04 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/hour_study_time/</guid>
      <description>Trying out something new to get the Network Plus study material done from Testout. Going to study from 4 to 5 pm everyday!
Today got innturruped a bit but it was actually really good to study. I was also able take some notes. I probably didnt get as much video watching done as I would have liked but it felt really good to have the time set asde.
I am looking forward to this and hope to get alot done.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Grep skills</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/grep_skills/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 21 Mar 2024 23:03:32 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/grep_skills/</guid>
      <description>I am enjoying my new Networking course from Cisco Skills for All. Its free and I think its good so far.
I was taking notes when I wanted to make ASCII art box around the tile and I knew I made a blog post about it&amp;hellip; So I looked up the blog post and re-read my instructions but I saw !! instead of !. So I needed to edit the .</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>3 Marathons</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/3_marathons/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 20 Mar 2024 22:28:17 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/3_marathons/</guid>
      <description>I am really looking forward to three races.
Madrid: I cant wait to go back. I just cant wait. I cant believe it either. Copenhagen: I cant say much more than I am stoked. Helsinki: Will round out completing marathons around Scandinavia. This kinda blows my mind.
I am so excited.
I wont go to fast but that&amp;rsquo;s okay. I am there just to run. :)</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Sustainable construction</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sustainable_construction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 17 Mar 2024 22:32:20 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sustainable_construction/</guid>
      <description>So I am really happy that there are so many sustainable construction companies in Colorado. For the summer, I am taking part in a 7 day construction workshop and then later in the summer a 3 day plaster workshop.
What I want to get out of this is threefold:
Learn more trades Meet more people Increase awairness of sustainable construction. I do still wish I had my own property and my own house to practice these techniques.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Gamification</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/gamification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 22:58:19 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/gamification/</guid>
      <description>Well, I have two big things coming up which will take alot of time.
Colorado Rail Game Network+ Both are huge goals and after reviewing all my ideas for the Rail Game and re-visiting the TestOut coursework for Network+ I feel like I am prepared to tackle them.
For the game, there is so much that I can draw upon from recent events and historical events, that I feel like the story will come together pretty easily.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Network&#43; back into focus</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/network&#43;_back_into_focus/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 11 Mar 2024 21:31:08 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/network&#43;_back_into_focus/</guid>
      <description>The Network+ course is back into my life.
Back when I when I was answering support tickets, and getting tired of it, I started to believe there could be a different future for my career.
I had spent years trying to learn to code on TeamTreeHouse. Weekends trying to learn to put projects together. I just was not having much success, thinking that becoming a programmer was a overnight thing.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Pyramid Principle</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/pyramid_principle/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 23:36:05 -0600</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/pyramid_principle/</guid>
      <description>I am glad I am taking so many online courses as I think it is giving me better skills that I can immididate use.
Take for example Firm Learning, which is for consultants but I paid for the &amp;lsquo;Communications and Slide Writing Academy.&amp;rsquo; This is where I learned how to write slides, or even blog posts about structuring a online for all kinds of documents. First, you outline the most important item you want to convey.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>SQL Quiz and drawing boxes and ASCII art with Boxes</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sql_quiz/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 09 Mar 2024 10:28:31 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/sql_quiz/</guid>
      <description>While taking my online course SQL for Data Science on Coursera, I really under estimated that the exams would be quite long with alot of queries. It was pretty painful to get my head thinking about how to write them and I was getting pretty impatient.
However, writing these queries is getting me excited when I eventually learn how to write in Go and be able to connect my app with the database.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Neovim_win</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/neovim_win/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 02 Mar 2024 10:09:03 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/neovim_win/</guid>
      <description>Looking back When I first learned about VIM, it blew my mind that you didnt need a mouse. It took me a while to get used to VIM motions but I can still look back to that day when I felt like a real programmer. Now fast forward some years and I am learning TMUX and that seems like a like another milestone in learning programming. To be able to pickup up wher I left off on one computer and start on another is suck a game changer, let alone when I forget to sign off and my pipe gets disconnected.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Accomplishing_a_tech_goal</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/accomplishing_a_tech_goal/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 27 Feb 2024 16:12:21 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/accomplishing_a_tech_goal/</guid>
      <description>Since migrating this website, I am seeing what I used to have and what I have now. It reminded me that I also have an about page on Github. So when I looked at that I decided to move that over to the about page on this website. When reading it, I realized that I had a &amp;ldquo;Tech Goal&amp;rdquo; of &amp;ldquo;Creating a blog with either django or Go about my coding journey.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Asking_the_question</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/asking_the_question/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 22:34:18 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/asking_the_question/</guid>
      <description>Today I had a common theme of asking the question.
In a meeting, I asked the same question twice for someone to answered it. In a group chat for a project management technical apprenticeship program I asked if anybody wants to join me in making docs and templates. I asked open ended questions in emails. I asked where I could get information from another team. So, never be afraid to ask questions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Went_with_HUGO</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/went_with_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 22:07:34 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/went_with_hugo/</guid>
      <description>I am putting all my old blog posts into Hugo it took a while as I basically have never done a large hugo site.
I think I understand the structure of HUGO.
I like it uses Markdown.
But I wish I had more control over the theme.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using_i3_on_a_old_laptop</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/using_i3_on_a_old_laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 22:04:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/using_i3_on_a_old_laptop/</guid>
      <description>On a old Dell laptop I have Fedora installed and usually I use GNOME but I also have i3.
I love i3. I wish I had it on another computer as I love just having three workspaces and just need something that is fast. They are usually Firefox, Terminal/Alacrity with Neovim/SSH/TMUX and the third workspace is a mix of terminal and browser. I really enjoy i3 and wish I had it on my work computer as its windows and it gets in the way of me being productive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying_out_shells</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/trying_out_shells/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 22:03:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/trying_out_shells/</guid>
      <description>Currently using Alacritty but did try out Warp, but it had to much unused space. I usually use iTerm as my regular Terminal app broke with my NeoVim font settings.
Want to have a low power terminal, and be able to try something new. So far I am liking Warp.
With Warp, I also found that I didnt need all the features as all you really need to know is TMUX.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting_back_my_online_study</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/getting_back_my_online_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 22:02:18 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/getting_back_my_online_study/</guid>
      <description>Been busy with work so that in the evening I don&amp;rsquo;t have energy to study my online courses. I am finally getting back to online learning after taking about 7 days off.
Doing the SQL and Tableau courses are shorter so I really need to study hard to finish them both.
I go back to Python on Boot.Dev to keep my coding knowledge stills fresh but I do miss Go on Coursera, as I want to make my website with Go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning&#43;Hobbies&#43;Time</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learning&#43;hobbies&#43;time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 22:01:01 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learning&#43;hobbies&#43;time/</guid>
      <description>I think having a part time job would be best way to make time for learning and side projects. I have never had a part time job, so that will be weird. Finding motivation right now is kinda hard with a fill like job that has FTO as i cant control things breaking or projects.
I was thinking of barista but i wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind having a outdoor job working with plants or some kind sustainable construction job.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyperloop_Twitter</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/hyperloop_twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 21:56:15 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/hyperloop_twitter/</guid>
      <description>After not having Twitter on my phone for months, I finally logged in to see what Hyperloop groups were still active. Unsurprisingly many of the European groups were still tweeting, and much fud was being said in the #hyperloop search.
I would like to do a video again soon but I am not sure I have time.
It takes time to write a scrip and I just dont have the energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advocacy&#43;Games&#43;Coding</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/advocacy&#43;games&#43;coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 21:54:33 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/advocacy&#43;games&#43;coding/</guid>
      <description>I was in the pool and thinking of how I can combine many different hobbies and learn how to code. So I came up with a project:
Online and free Similar to Oregon Trail, as it will be pixel based and have story lines for the choices you make. Take donations and be able to sell merch Will help me learn to code Be able to do some public advocacy for sustainable transportation for Colorado.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online_learning_costs_and_time</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/online_learning_costs_and_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 21:52:50 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/online_learning_costs_and_time/</guid>
      <description>I thought I would just write down how much time and money I have spent for continuing education and professional development.
$349.00 for a lab simulator for Network+ TestOut and I have not completed it for over a year. $434.15 each year for 2+ years for Coursera Plus for Google Project Management and Google IT Support Free access to Pluralsight via my work which took me around 3 months: Network Security Basics, VLAN Operation and Con figuration, Network Troubleshooting and Tools, Ethernet Operation and Switch Configuration, Network Management and Operations, Introduction Enterprise Network Infrastructure, Network Concepts and Protocols Over $600 on other miscellaneous educational stuff over the last three years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 21:51:31 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Its hard re-learning how to type on a new Kenesis Advantage 2 QD keyboard. However, its much better on my wrists. But I will try and keep using it every day. My first thought when taking notes is how much I have to look down at my fingers and then how I am using my fingers to type with the incorrect finger per key. Always overwhelming learning new things but glad I am doing it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UX_in_online_courses</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/ux_in_online_courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 21:50:16 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/ux_in_online_courses/</guid>
      <description>I am in Coursera most of the time for online courses and I have a few recommendations on how they could make finishing courses better for users like me.
Make a dark mode. None of the website can be toggled to eye friendly dark mode and this is a huge as we are putting a ton of screentime into watching their videos and takeing exams in front of white sreen that is painful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open_source_app_idea</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/open_source_app_idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 21:42:24 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/open_source_app_idea/</guid>
      <description>The idea is to make a app that can be used on a phone where it will track door lock installs. Features:
Connect to a API for hardware components etc Be able to export to CSV or spreadsheet Take photos and save media Real time CRUD database Drop pins on a blueprint overlay Be able to add other data like access control for groups etc Project track site survey, fabrication, change orders, show a visual timeline, install and track completion tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40_Marathons_before_40</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/40_marathons_before_40/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 21:41:02 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/40_marathons_before_40/</guid>
      <description>Another blog post about exercise, but this one is a big goal. 40 Marathons before I am 40. I am not 100% sure how many marathons I have run so far, will need to recount. However, I think this goal will be great as it will give a bunch of strucutre, and will be a great way to do perhaps other marathons in other contries. Also a great excuse to travel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swimming</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/swimming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 21:39:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/swimming/</guid>
      <description>The blog post title was going to be exercise but I want to talk more about swimming in particular. I want to talk about being in the pool for a couple of reasons.
Swimming gives you gains. It makes you really buff without having to lift weights. Its basially like yoga and afterwards I think it makes you feel just as relaxed. The pool is very rairly busy, so its super easy to get in and do the 1500 meters and then get out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 21:38:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/2024/</guid>
      <description>Some goals for 2024 from the top of my mind:
Run more, or even every day, including more marathons Learn bagpipes Finish more of my certificates Continue to get better at Neovim and submit to Github almost every day Travel more and do projects when I travel like straw bale projectes Cook more Wear more sunscreen Who knows how these goals will go over time but i feel like my goals in life are becoming more focused and are more fun to accomplish.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unexpected_AI</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/unexpected_ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 21:37:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/unexpected_ai/</guid>
      <description>While choosing what to study tonight, I decided to go back to learning Python and Go on Boot.Dev. Its been some weeks since I last did a bit of python, so I was trying to remember how to do things and was asked a tricky question on one of the code challenges.
Instead of just clicking hint, I decided to use the AI chat bot &amp;ldquo;boots&amp;rdquo; for the first time ever.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video_Games_and_Self Study</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/video_games_and_self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 21:35:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/video_games_and_self-study/</guid>
      <description>I think about Video Games a lot. I also play alot. From Civ to City Skylines to my latest favorite, Starfield. I like thinking during the day about what I want to build or do when later in the evening I get to play.
On the flip coin, I also think about what I want to study or learn about in the evening. I signed up for even more courses last night.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workout_and_Goals</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/workout_and_goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 21:33:40 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/workout_and_goals/</guid>
      <description>This has been a busy week of work, so on Friday I went out of my way to go to the pool and swim just a bit, and on Saturday I went again with the goal of going really far.
Back in 2018 did a challenge with my triathlon club to do either 10k or 5k distance swim at the end of the new year. After completing the 5k challenge in the cold DAC pool, I really felt accomplished.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data_Vis,_Hyperloop_and_Bumper_Stickers</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/data_vis_hyperloop_and_bumper_stickers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 21:27:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/data_vis_hyperloop_and_bumper_stickers/</guid>
      <description>Learning data vis in Tableau right now. I wish I had learned this earlier in my work as I think I could have used it.
I still keep thinking of my goal to make some kind of website or game where you can see hyperloop pods going around their tracks. When I am learning Tableau I am using data from the Global Hyperloop Challenge where I pitched &amp;lsquo;Colorado Hyperloop.&amp;rsquo;
After my support of something very futuristic, I am wanting to create merch and bumper stickers that promote a Front Range Passenger Rail in Colorado.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work_goals</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/work_goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 21:25:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/work_goals/</guid>
      <description>I have three short term work goals that I either do at night or work on when I dont have other things to do at work:
Study the Data Analystics course by Google and copy down the job post I read about it to then get those skills. Create the project management template for initial conversations with stakeholders about projects with Hospitality IT. Figure out a project with Sustainability staff that would augment my development of a leadership skill.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning_goals</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learning_goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 21:20:04 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learning_goals/</guid>
      <description>I think my goals for the Data Analyst courses is just to make more templates. When people have ideas, or I have an idea, I need a way to show how those ideas, goals or projects can come together visually so everyone can see risks, goals and the end result. Stopping and thinking about projects is always a good idea. So I hope these templates can help me at work better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self_study_job</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/self_study_job/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 21:24:17 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/self_study_job/</guid>
      <description>In writing this blog, I cant stop thinking about all the past jobs and personal study and sacrifice it took to get here. I see my Github history and I can see the first commits were Oct 31, 2011. I had no idea what I was doing, but I was in a bootcamp trying to will myself to learn.
I think the main lesson is that its taken me 12 years to get where I am now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn_to_break_code</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learn_to_break_code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learn_to_break_code/</guid>
      <description>I have spent so many years trying to learn to code, so I am going to try and learn by not having any fear on getting a project, then write code or get code from the example, then try and break it. I should not be taking notes anymore, but rather get muscle memory in interacting with code more. So will I take hints on writing code? Yes. But I will try and break it more often to see how it works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notetaking_workflow</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/notetaking_workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/notetaking_workflow/</guid>
      <description>Below is a half written vlog post on how it has taken me 5 years to hone in on how to take notes from online courses as well as learn tools and technology.
1. I was working for a domain name company and one of the senior engineers recommended that I learn Vim.This got me down the rabbit hole of learning how to interact with a computer applications only by using the keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using_Go_or_Python_for_this_blog</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/using_go_or_python_for_this_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/using_go_or_python_for_this_blog/</guid>
      <description>I have been wanting to use what I am learning to make this blog better. I was thinking I would use Python from my boot.dev course and then learn Django. However, I am now leaning to Hugo and take a risk as I do not know Go.
I am still trying to figure out a way to learn and make time during the day to do online courses and projects/tasks like upgrade this blog.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
