<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom" xmlns:content="http://purl.org/rss/1.0/modules/content/">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on BlakeAnneberg.com</title>
    <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on BlakeAnneberg.com</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 22:34:18 -0700</lastBuildDate>
    <atom:link href="https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Asking_the_question</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/asking_the_question/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 26 Feb 2024 22:34:18 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/asking_the_question/</guid>
      <description>Today I had a common theme of asking the question.
In a meeting, I asked the same question twice for someone to answered it. In a group chat for a project management technical apprenticeship program I asked if anybody wants to join me in making docs and templates. I asked open ended questions in emails. I asked where I could get information from another team. So, never be afraid to ask questions.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Went_with_HUGO</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/went_with_hugo/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 25 Feb 2024 22:07:34 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/went_with_hugo/</guid>
      <description>I am putting all my old blog posts into Hugo… it took a while as I basically have never done a large hugo site.
I think I understand the structure of HUGO.
I like it uses Markdown.
But I wish I had more control over the theme.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using_i3_on_a_old_laptop</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/using_i3_on_a_old_laptop/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Feb 2024 22:04:38 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/using_i3_on_a_old_laptop/</guid>
      <description>On a old Dell laptop I have Fedora installed and usually I use GNOME but I also have i3.
I love i3. I wish I had it on another computer as I love just having three workspaces and just need something that is fast. They are usually Firefox, Terminal/Alacrity with Neovim/SSH/TMUX and the third workspace is a mix of terminal and browser. I really enjoy i3 and wish I had it on my work computer as its windows and it gets in the way of me being productive.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Trying_out_shells</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/trying_out_shells/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 11 Feb 2024 22:03:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/trying_out_shells/</guid>
      <description>Currently using Alacritty but did try out Warp, but it had to much unused space. I usually use iTerm as my regular Terminal app broke with my NeoVim font settings.
Want to have a low power terminal, and be able to try something new. So far I am liking Warp.
With Warp, I also found that I didnt need all the features as all you really need to know is TMUX.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Getting_back_my_online_study</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/getting_back_my_online_study/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 10 Feb 2024 22:02:18 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/getting_back_my_online_study/</guid>
      <description>Been busy with work so that in the evening I don&amp;rsquo;t have energy to study my online courses. I am finally getting back to online learning after taking about 7 days off.
Doing the SQL and Tableau courses are shorter so I really need to study hard to finish them both.
I go back to Python on Boot.Dev to keep my coding knowledge stills fresh but I do miss Go on Coursera, as I want to make my website with Go.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning&#43;Hobbies&#43;Time</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learning&#43;hobbies&#43;time/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 03 Feb 2024 22:01:01 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learning&#43;hobbies&#43;time/</guid>
      <description>I think having a part time job would be best way to make time for learning and side projects. I have never had a part time job, so that will be weird. Finding motivation right now is kinda hard with a fill like job that has FTO as i cant control things breaking or projects.
I was thinking of barista but i wouldn&amp;rsquo;t mind having a outdoor job working with plants or some kind sustainable construction job.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Hyperloop_Twitter</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/hyperloop_twitter/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 31 Jan 2024 21:56:15 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/hyperloop_twitter/</guid>
      <description>After not having Twitter on my phone for months, I finally logged in to see what Hyperloop groups were still active. Unsurprisingly many of the European groups were still tweeting, and much fud was being said in the #hyperloop search.
I would like to do a video again soon but I am not sure I have time.
It takes time to write a scrip and I just dont have the energy.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Advocacy&#43;Games&#43;Coding</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/advocacy&#43;games&#43;coding/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 21 Jan 2024 21:54:33 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/advocacy&#43;games&#43;coding/</guid>
      <description>I was in the pool and thinking of how I can combine many different hobbies and learn how to code. So I came up with a project:
Online and free Similar to Oregon Trail, as it will be pixel based and have story lines for the choices you make. Take donations and be able to sell merch Will help me learn to code Be able to do some public advocacy for sustainable transportation for Colorado.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Online_learning_costs_and_time</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/online_learning_costs_and_time/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 18 Jan 2024 21:52:50 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/online_learning_costs_and_time/</guid>
      <description>I thought I would just write down how much time and money I have spent for continuing education and professional development.
$349.00 for a lab simulator for Network+ TestOut and I have not completed it for over a year. $434.15 each year for 2+ years for Coursera Plus for Google Project Management and Google IT Support Free access to Pluralsight via my work which took me around 3 months: Network Security Basics, VLAN Operation and Con figuration, Network Troubleshooting and Tools, Ethernet Operation and Switch Configuration, Network Management and Operations, Introduction Enterprise Network Infrastructure, Network Concepts and Protocols Over $600 on other miscellaneous educational stuff over the last three years.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Keyboard</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/keyboard/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 14 Jan 2024 21:51:31 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/keyboard/</guid>
      <description>Its hard re-learning how to type on a new Kenesis Advantage 2 QD keyboard. However, its much better on my wrists. But I will try and keep using it every day. My first thought when taking notes is how much I have to look down at my fingers and then how I am using my fingers to type with the incorrect finger per key. Always overwhelming learning new things but glad I am doing it.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>UX_in_online_courses</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/ux_in_online_courses/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 12 Jan 2024 21:50:16 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/ux_in_online_courses/</guid>
      <description>I am in Coursera most of the time for online courses and I have a few recommendations on how they could make finishing courses better for users like me.
Make a dark mode. None of the website can be toggled to eye friendly dark mode and this is a huge as we are putting a ton of screentime into watching their videos and takeing exams in front of white sreen that is painful.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Open_source_app_idea</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/open_source_app_idea/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 08 Jan 2024 21:42:24 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/open_source_app_idea/</guid>
      <description>The idea is to make a app that can be used on a phone where it will track door lock installs. Features:
Connect to a API for hardware components etc Be able to export to CSV or spreadsheet Take photos and save media Real time CRUD database Drop pins on a blueprint overlay Be able to add other data like access control for groups etc Project track site survey, fabrication, change orders, show a visual timeline, install and track completion tasks.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>40_Marathons_before_40</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/40_marathons_before_40/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 06 Jan 2024 21:41:02 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/40_marathons_before_40/</guid>
      <description>Another blog post about exercise, but this one is a big goal. 40 Marathons before I am 40. I am not 100% sure how many marathons I have run so far, will need to recount. However, I think this goal will be great as it will give a bunch of strucutre, and will be a great way to do perhaps other marathons in other contries. Also a great excuse to travel.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Swimming</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/swimming/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 03 Jan 2024 21:39:44 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/swimming/</guid>
      <description>The blog post title was going to be exercise but I want to talk more about swimming in particular. I want to talk about being in the pool for a couple of reasons.
Swimming gives you gains. It makes you really buff without having to lift weights. Its basially like yoga and afterwards I think it makes you feel just as relaxed. The pool is very rairly busy, so its super easy to get in and do the 1500 meters and then get out.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>2024</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/2024/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 2024 21:38:12 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/2024/</guid>
      <description>Some goals for 2024 from the top of my mind:
Run more, or even every day, including more marathons Learn bagpipes Finish more of my certificates Continue to get better at Neovim and submit to Github almost every day Travel more and do projects when I travel like straw bale projectes Cook more Wear more sunscreen Who knows how these goals will go over time but i feel like my goals in life are becoming more focused and are more fun to accomplish.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Unexpected_AI</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/unexpected_ai/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 27 Dec 2023 21:37:09 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/unexpected_ai/</guid>
      <description>While choosing what to study tonight, I decided to go back to learning Python and Go on Boot.Dev. Its been some weeks since I last did a bit of python, so I was trying to remember how to do things and was asked a tricky question on one of the code challenges.
Instead of just clicking hint, I decided to use the AI chat bot &amp;ldquo;boots&amp;rdquo; for the first time ever.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Video_Games_and_Self Study</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/video_games_and_self-study/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 26 Dec 2023 21:35:07 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/video_games_and_self-study/</guid>
      <description>I think about Video Games a lot. I also play alot. From Civ to City Skylines to my latest favorite, Starfield. I like thinking during the day about what I want to build or do when later in the evening I get to play.
On the flip coin, I also think about what I want to study or learn about in the evening. I signed up for even more courses last night.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Workout_and_Goals</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/workout_and_goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 21:33:40 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/workout_and_goals/</guid>
      <description>This has been a busy week of work, so on Friday I went out of my way to go to the pool and swim just a bit, and on Saturday I went again with the goal of going really far.
Back in 2018 did a challenge with my triathlon club to do either 10k or 5k distance swim at the end of the new year. After completing the 5k challenge in the cold DAC pool, I really felt accomplished.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Data_Vis,_Hyperloop_and_Bumper_Stickers</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/data_vis_hyperloop_and_bumper_stickers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 16 Dec 2023 21:27:32 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/data_vis_hyperloop_and_bumper_stickers/</guid>
      <description>Learning data vis in Tableau right now. I wish I had learned this earlier in my work as I think I could have used it.
I still keep thinking of my goal to make some kind of website or game where you can see hyperloop pods going around their tracks. When I am learning Tableau I am using data from the Global Hyperloop Challenge where I pitched &amp;lsquo;Colorado Hyperloop.&amp;rsquo;
After my support of something very futuristic, I am wanting to create merch and bumper stickers that promote a Front Range Passenger Rail in Colorado.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Work_goals</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/work_goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 21:25:45 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/work_goals/</guid>
      <description>I have three short term work goals that I either do at night or work on when I dont have other things to do at work:
Study the Data Analystics course by Google and copy down the job post I read about it to then get those skills. Create the project management template for initial conversations with stakeholders about projects with Hospitality IT. Figure out a project with Sustainability staff that would augment my development of a leadership skill.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learning_goals</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learning_goals/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 27 Nov 2023 21:20:04 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learning_goals/</guid>
      <description>I think my goals for the Data Analyst courses is just to make more templates. When people have ideas, or I have an idea, I need a way to show how those ideas, goals or projects can come together visually so everyone can see risks, goals and the end result. Stopping and thinking about projects is always a good idea. So I hope these templates can help me at work better.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Self_study_job</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/self_study_job/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 12 Oct 2023 21:24:17 -0700</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/self_study_job/</guid>
      <description>In writing this blog, I cant stop thinking about all the past jobs and personal study and sacrifice it took to get here. I see my Github history and I can see the first commits were Oct 31, 2011. I had no idea what I was doing, but I was in a bootcamp trying to will myself to learn.
I think the main lesson is that its taken me 12 years to get where I am now.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Learn_to_break_code</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learn_to_break_code/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/learn_to_break_code/</guid>
      <description>I have spent so many years trying to learn to code, so I am going to try and learn by not having any fear on getting a project, then write code or get code from the example, then try and break it. I should not be taking notes anymore, but rather get muscle memory in interacting with code more. So will I take hints on writing code? Yes. But I will try and break it more often to see how it works.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Notetaking_workflow</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/notetaking_workflow/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/notetaking_workflow/</guid>
      <description>Below is a half written vlog post on how it has taken me 5 years to hone in on how to take notes from online courses as well as learn tools and technology.
1. I was working for a domain name company and one of the senior engineers recommended that I learn Vim.This got me down the rabbit hole of learning how to interact with a computer applications only by using the keyboard.</description>
    </item>
    <item>
      <title>Using_Go_or_Python_for_this_blog</title>
      <link>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/using_go_or_python_for_this_blog/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      <guid>https://blakeanneberg.com/posts/using_go_or_python_for_this_blog/</guid>
      <description>I have been wanting to use what I am learning to make this blog better. I was thinking I would use Python from my boot.dev course and then learn Django. However, I am now leaning to Hugo and take a risk as I do not know Go.
I am still trying to figure out a way to learn and make time during the day to do online courses and projects/tasks like upgrade this blog.</description>
    </item>
  </channel>
</rss>
